<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-susan-b-anthony</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/=https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058130/1883-02-25/ed-1/seq-7/#words=Anthony+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text> Susan B. Anthony
Miss Susan Brownell Anthony
whose name has been familiar to
the public in the United States for I
more than thirty years is about to
leave this country for a long sojourn
in Great Britain and France Miss
Anthony intends however to make
her European trip no mere voyage
of recreation for she has in view
the continuation in foreign lands of I
the earnest and laborious work in
behalf of womankind to which she
has so long and so conspicuously
devoted herself in her native coun
try Miss Anthony haS not suc
ceeded in convincing a majority of i
intelligent Americans of the wis
dom of according the right of
suffrage to women but her sin
cerity and the firmness with which
she has upheld her individual I
belief upon all occasions have
won for her the esteem if not the
support 01 the influential portion
of this community Miss Anthony
believes that the cause for which
she has worked has made much
progress latterly and she probably
thinks that it will be ultimately
successful and although it is not
likely that the advocates of the ex
tension of suffrage to women in this
country are numerically stronger
today in proportion to the popula
tion than they were thirty years
ago yet it will be conceded that the
agitation for womans rights 4ias
produced good results in the amelio
ration of the condition of women
and their administration as co
laborers with men in many branches
of industry Miss Susan U
Anthony is now nearly 63 years
of age she was born at North
Adams Mass and her ancestors
were Quakers she was educated in
the city of Philadelphia and began
in that peaceful settlement her
philanthropic labors The Phila
delphia Times learns that Miss
Anthonys departure which will be
made from that city on the 21st
instant will be preceded by a pub
lic reception to the distinguished
lady on the 19th instant when some
of her associates will felicitate her
and themselves upon the good work
they have accomplished and bid her
godspeed and success in her mission
to less enlightened lands It is
pleasing to learn thatMiss Anthony
who has used a large share of a
I small income for many years to
benefit others has recently fallen
I heir to a considerable sun pf money
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064537/1885-02-07/ed-1/seq-8/#words=Anthony+B+Church+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
Miss Susan B. Anthony and Mrs.
Elizabeth Cady Stanton, and on
the conclusion of the services they
walked to the platform and up
braided Dr. Patten for his utter
ances.
Miss Anthony said to Iii m if Iiis
mother were living she shouM t i ke
"him across her knee and spank him,
but Mrs. Stanton, interrupting her
said : "On the contrary : let me con
gratulate Dr. Patten. I have been
tr.ying for years to make women un
derstand that the worst enemies
they have are in the pulpit, and
now Le has illustrated it beyond
question."
Without giving Dr. Patten time
to reply the women hastily left the
church. To-nig-ht Rev. «Olympia
P. Brown replied to Dr. Patten
from the pulpit of the Universalist
Church.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86071868/1893-01-22/ed-1/seq-3/#words=Anthony+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Susan B. Anthony, Elizabeth Cady
Stanton, Isabella Beecher Hooker and
Lucy Stone, must bo placed the active
list of younger workers, such as Rev.
Anna Shaw, Rachel Foster A very, Lucy
E. Anthony, May Wright Bewail, Alice
Stone Blackwell and Harriet Taylor
Upton.
Though this is a quarter century con?
vention, it is by no means proper to in?
fer that the movement in America had
its inception twent3'-flve years ago. It
was Mrs. Stanton, still a member, who,
in 1848, almost half a century ago, as?
sisted by Lucretia Mott, called the first
convention at Seneca Falls. The de?
mand for equal suffrage was as broad
then as it is now. In its purpose the
movement has never grown. In its
elaboration and application it has as?
sumed splendid proportions.
The declaration of sentiments enunci?
ated at that first convention recited
among other grievances those growing
out of the legal disabilities of women,
the injustice of taxation without repre?
sentation, lack of higher educational
facilities nnd finally the resolution:
"That it is the duty of the women of
this country to secure to themselves
the sacred right to the elective fran?
chise."
Two years later Susan B. Anthony
joined the movement and the Quaker
girl of those early days put. heart, soul
and mind into the movement, and much
of the work achieved must be credited
to her.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85047084/1894-04-30/ed-1/seq-6/#words=Anthony+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The bravest battle that ever wa
fought" is that fought by the woman
suffragi3t3. Susan B. Anthony declares
that if in the battle now going on for
suffrage in New York state the men do
not vote as they should, she will come
back a3 a spook and haunt them. "I
shall certainly return," she says, "and
they will find me a troublesome sister."
Mis3 Anthony i3 now 74 years old, but
looks much the same as she did 20
years ago. In a recent speech at Schen
ectady she said she had been in the
newspaper business once. In that
venture she lost all the money she
had saved at schoolteaching and went
110,000 in debt. The paper was The
Revolution, a weekly published in New
York city f o advocate woman's rights.
Mis3 Anthony and Elizabeth Cady Stan
ton were editors, with Parker Pillabury
as editorial contributor. It was able,
and brilliant, but for some reason it
failed to be a go, and it wa3 abandoned
when it had rolled up the $10,000 debt.
Susan Anthony, with the pluck and hon
esty characteristic of thi3 great woman,
resolved that no creditors should suffer
loss through her. She undertook the
task of paying all the debt herself and
did so. Women lecturers were mere cf
a rarity 2" year3 ago than they are now,
and Susan entered the general lecture
field. Lectures, too, were more popular
then than they are now, and in six
years she had paid every dollar of The
Revolution debt. "Then I had a ju
bilee.V exclaimed Miss Anthony. She
lectured six years more. "I made enough
money to live on, and I am living on it
yet," she explained. As soon as she had
laid up enough to support herself mod
estly she turned her back forever on the
general lecture field and devoted her life
henceforth to working for women. "I
can get $50 to $ 100 a night to lecture, but
I feel that the cause needs me, and I am
devoting my time and energies to that
cause." One theme which she is putting
before her audiences this winter is the
powerlessness of disfranchised classes to
make, shape and control their own con
ditions moral and industrial as well as
political.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1905-07-28/ed-1/seq-14/#words=Anthony+ANTHONY+SUSAN+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SUFFRAGE LEADER
  I Susan n. Anthony and her party of
' distinguished woman suffrage workers
' srrlved In Los Angeles yesterday morn
ing at 11:30 o'clock,
j Just nine years ago the same leader
of the once most unpopular of reform
movements mado a visit to Los An
geles, but those who saw her yester
day declare that if Los Angeles has
aged In nine years Susan B. Anthony
lias not. She does not look a day
-'(older and would not thank anyone for
even suggesting that she is feeble.
It was a group of splendid young-old
women gathered In the drawing room
of Mrs. Wills' home yesterday af ter-
Vioon when a reporter called. Susan B.
Anthony, Rev. Anna Shaw and Mrs.
, Charlotte Wills, three veterans in the
suffrage work, each with hair that has
long been white, but each with the flre
'of youth and battle in her eyes, which
years have failed to deaden.
"Yes," said Miss Anthony, "I am feel-
Ing as well as ever, and expect to spend
many years fighting for the cause most
dear to me.
Public Sentiment Changes
"The time has gone by when the
' cause can only be laughed at, and
every day we find new evidences of
the wonderful change in public senti
ment in favor of equal suffrage. Since
we were here nine years ago there has
been a revolution of feeling."
v "Tou see we have just come from
Oregon," added Rev. Dr. Shaw, "and
' both Miss Anthony and I were so
Rleased with our campaign in that
'.state and the encouragement we re
ceived at the hands of politicians we
- cannot help dwelling on this. Suffrage
is Inevitable."
. ... , Criticise Library Board
V& Both women spoke of the library con
troversy and both attended the meeting
in the council chamber last evening.
' "This library question should be an
j excellent argument in favor of women
having the ballot," said Miss Anthony,
"Every day similar questions come up
all; over the country. Women have
their positions taken from them just
. because they are unable to defend
* themselves with the ballot.
, . ,"I wonder why it is that the city of
I Los Angeles can afford to pay Mr.
Lummis one hundred dollars a month
more than Miss Jones without even
trying him. How has be proved himself
a hundred dollars a month more val
. uable than the woman whose place he
will take?"
! Today Miss Anthony and the mem
bers of her party ; will be honored
guests at a reception given by Los An
geles' club women at the Woman's club
bouse.
■ Tuesday Rev. Anna Shaw will speak
twice before the Venice assembly.
.Tuesday afternoon a suffrage sympos
ium will be held at Venice and well
known local speakers will also take
part in the program with the visitors.
On Wednesday morning Dr. Shaw will
leave for San Francisco en route to the
feast. She will speak at twelve conven
tions in various states. Susan B. An
thony will return to her home.
Miss Anthony and Rev. Shaw are the
guests of Mrs. Charlotte Wills of 501
Buena Vista street, while Mrs. Edward
L. Doheny of 8 Chester place Is enter
taining Mrs. Emily B. Gross and Dr.
Mary Hussy of Chicago, the last named
being a daughter of the woman who re
cently donated $10,000 to the National
Suffragists' association.
Miss Jessie Anthony of Los Angeles,
a cousin of the lecturer, has as her
guest Miss Lucy Anthony, private sec
retary to Mrs. Shaw, and Miss Mary
A. Anthony, sister of Miss Susan B.
Anthony, is the guest of Madame Car
oline M. Severance of 806 West Adams
street.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92053934/1906-03-13/ed-1/seq-6/#words=Anthony+B+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Miss Susan B. Anthony. Long
Head of Woman's Suffrage
Move, Dies. V
PNEUMONIA FATAL DISEASE
Lived to See Marked Change n Pop
ular Estimate of Her
Work.
Rochester, X. Y., March 13. The
long and eventful life of Susan B. An
thony closed at 12:40 this morning.
The end came peacefully. Miss An
thony had been unconscious practical
ly, for 24 hours, and her death has
been momentarily expected since Snn-
1
m
V
1
' ;.'W ;::; SJi-'i
it
1 . '-ljfi -
5
A brief meeting of the democratic
city township committee was held last
evening at the Rock Island house par
lors, for the purpose of organization.
The meeting was held on the call of,stW"l in -New York ; where a, ban
BtJSAN B. ANTHONY.
,
day night. Only her wonderful consti
tution kept her alive. Dr. Ricker, her
attending physician, said Miss An
thony died of heart failure induced by
double pneumonia.
Miss Anthony was taken ill while
on her way homo from, tha National
Suffrage convention in Baltimore. She
Chairman George Wright. The newly
lected committee reelected Mr.
Wright as chairman, and also reelected
,T. P. Sexton secretary of the commit-
to. The elections were unanimous.
Mrfla C'antlidnteM.
The committee adjourned after mak
quet was to be given leb. 20, in honor
of-her -SUth birthday, but' she had an
attack of neuralgia on thelSth, and
hastened home, pneumonia developing
after her arrival here. '
Smv fhnnfcp In Sentiment.
Mifs Anthony Jived to see a decided
ins arrangements for a conference of " , - ' -
iur iiiir-i ji j.ui wiit'ii &ucf wus iiiris-
the committee and the candidates for
olfice in the town and city election
I.CF UB III 111 IUUIUI ivn at. hMi
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1916-03-15/ed-1/seq-8/#words=Anthony+Susan</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>WOMEN ORGANIZE IN SIXTH
CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT
The Congressional Union for Wom
an Suffrage will hold its first meeting
in the Sixth congressional district at
the home of Dr. Linslay Wynkoop,
3406 Monroe st, at 2 p. m., Thurs
day. The meeting will "be for the pur
pose of organizing this district that it
may, with similar organizations in
every congressional district, force
immediate action on the Susan B.
Anthony amendment
Mrs. Gilson Gardner of Washing
ton, D. C, a member of the executive
committee of the union, and Elsie Hill
will speak.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2013218776/1920-09-04/ed-1/seq-3/#words=Anthony+ANTHONY+SUSAN+Susan</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Quakeress Begins, Another Ends Votes Fight
Campaign for Suffrage Amendment Started by Susan B. Anthony
Carried to Victory by Alice Paul When Tennessee Ratines
STARTED by a Quaker girl; finished by a Quaker
girl! That's the strangely romantic history of
the suffrage amendment to the Constitution of the
United States. All of this possibly proves that the
oft-repeated proverbial demureiuss of Quaker maidens
may run true to ancient form when it comes to a case
of springtime courtship, but that it has no place in
their mental determination when they feel that great
national principles arc mvoiveu.
ticu
an
Perhaps it's time we stopped referring to some par
llar person as having the "tenacity of a bulldog,"
Q
By H. O. BISHOP
for standing by her principles. This occurred in 1872
when she sought to test the Fourteenth and Fifteenth
Amendments by casting a ballot at the state and con
gressional elections at her home town. She was indicted
and a fine imposed for the offense. Instead of paying
the fine she merely looked the judge in the eye and
defiantly said : "May it please your honor, I will
never pay a dollar of your unjust penalty and I shall
earnestly and persistently continue to urge all women
to the practical recognition of the old revolutionary
maxim that resistance to tyranny is obedience
to God."
Thp Federal miffratrp amrnrlmpnt Hrnfterf hv
Miss Anthony, in 1875, introduced into Congress
in 1878, and finally passed in 1919, reads: "The
right of citizens of the United States to vote shall
not be denied or abridged by the United States or
by any state on account of sex."
In the early days of her lecturing Miss Anthony
arrayed herself in bloomers, but soon discarded
them for the reason that they attracted more at
tention than the subject under discussion.
The idea of tying up with neither Democratic
nor Republican party originated with Miss An
thony, her plan being to root for the Democrats in
any state where they cast fond glances suffrage
ward, and to boost for the Republicans in other
states if they manifested any fondness toward
ballots for women. The same effective prin
ciple of campaigning was later adopted with
remarkable success by the Anti-Saloon League.
The American Federation of Labor, under the
leadership of Samuel Gompers, is planning to
follow the same idea in the coming campaign.
The Republicans were the first to advocate
equal suffrage. In their platform in 1872, they
inserted this mild plank so mild as to be not
more than a board : "The Republican party is
mindful of its obligations to the loyal women
.UiUI Wf n J - OF
id say instead : "They have the tenacity of a
linker." In the light of present-day events it would
,-n miirh more exnressive.
JCll" 1
Susan Bromwell Anthony was the Quakeress who
drafted the suffrage amend-
. 1 07C 1C -
mem in ioi j tj iai s ago
and pedicted its success in
1920.
Alice Paul is the Quaker
ess who is credited with the
never-say-die style of political
generalship which has recently
made the Anthony Amend
ment a part of the Constitu
tion of the United States. Miss
Anthony was as much of a
fighting Quaker in her
day as Alexander Mitch
ell Palmer, Attorney
General, is credited with
being today. Mr. Palmer,
it will be recalled, de
clined the appointment
of Secretary of War,
tendered by President
Wilson, on the ground
that his religion was
against war. Later he
was an aspirant for the
big job of Commander-in-Chief
of the Army
and Navy of the United
States. Evidently the
Quaker religion does not
object to big jobs of
fighting; such as, lead
ing the army and navy
or putting over a Con
stitutional amendment.
And when it comes
to double A, triple X.
dye d-in-the-w o o 1 and
fight-it-to-a-finish brand
of militancy, neither
Miss Anthony nor Mr.
Palmer ever displayed
better staying qualities
than Alice Paul.
Miss Anthony was
born in Massachusetts
just a hundred years
ago. When she was six
years of age, the family,
apparently wearied of
looking at and hearing
about Plymouth Rock,
moved to Washington
County, New York.
Twenty years later they moved to Rochester,
in the same state. Between the advertising
received through Miss Anthony and a kodak
factory, Rochester has succeeded in becoming
one of the best-known cities in the world.
When seventeen, Miss Anthony taught
school at a salary of $1.50 weekly This
munificent income was all velvet, as it was
the custom in those days for teachers to
"board .round" among the parents of the pu
pils. The probabilities are that her salary ot
that day had as great or greater purchasing
power as some of the salaries of public school
teachers today. Had it not been for the sar
casm of the male chairman of a temperance convey
tion held at Albany, New York in 1852, it Ple
that the Quaker ire of Miss Anthony would alwas
have remained calm and peaceful and she would have
continued teaching school or married some likely
young chap and lived serenely and demurely ejff alter
instead of starting a suffrage rumpus that s c,s"
many gray hairs to sprout on the heads of Democratic
and Republican leaders in this good year ot ivu.
She was attending the convention of the ons oi
Temperance as a delegate from the daughters ot
Temperance of Rochester. During one of the tense
periods of discussion, Miss Anthony rose to . ner teci
to speak on a motion before the house. To her utter
surprise the chairman leaned forward over the speaK
er's table and in red-faced anger announced that tne
sisters were not invited there to speak but to listen
and to learn." M ... .
Right there is where that old boy spilled the
beans and they have never been picked up since, as
a result of his bull-headed ruling, equal suffrage soon
became a live political issue and has been getting
livelier ever since. Iwo years later jm
activitv rui1tr1 in ciifTracrr convention
in every county in New York. . . , she was graduated from Swartnmore at
A She attempted to have the vote given to women at scho . received degree, of ;M. A and Ph . O.
"ic ume tne Negroes were entrancing, - , thc university oi rennsyi-i. zzl
to wait a while as "that was the Negroes hour. Lthering of this crop of education, she went to Lon-
Susan Anthony was the first woman to be arrested gatneri 8
(C) Harris & Ewing
MISS ALICE PAUL
The Quaker f irl who gencraled the
job of paatind and ratifying the
suffrage amendment.
Sl
SUSAN BROMWELL ANTHONY
The Quakereaa who etarted the movement for a suffrage amendment.
of America for their noble devotion to the cause of
freedom; their admission to wider fields of usefulness
is received with satisfaction ; and the honest demands
of any class of citizens for equal rights should be
treated with respectful consideration.
In an effort to "play both ends against the mid
dle,' Miss Anthony prepared a letter for the New
York World "calling upon the Democrats to adopt a
woman suffrage plank if they did not wish to compel
the women of the country to work for the success
of the Republican ticket."
Miss Anthony went to her reward in 1906.
It was in 1913 that Alice Paul made her appear
ance at Washington, D. C, and started to smash
staid traditions into smithereens. Old-time politicians
foon commenced referring to her as 'that darn
SSaWfH from Jersey who is the smoothest poli
tician in the countir.; wh.rnme .definite spot
been getting Z otUM having selected it
iss Anthony s on the map as a 3 years ago.
g being held as her b,r hptace. wh. cn p Qua
school. She was graauaicu iw -
twenty, and later received degrees of.M. A- and Ph a
fthe University oi"
don to prepare a thesis on the position of women and
to study economics. While in London she did settle
ment work and assisted in the suffrage campaign in
England. Later she engaged in settlement work in
New York.
When Alice Paul arrived in Washington in 1913,
she came without money, without influence, armed only
with the conviction that the time had come to win.
Beginning with a small basement office, with a few
ardent followers who did everything from making
street corner speeches to licking stamps, she built up
a nation-wide organization of women, with branches
and officers in every state, bound together by the pledge
to regard "woman suffrage as the foremost political
issue of the day, supporting it irrespective of the in
terests of any political party."
So effective was Miss Paul's leadership that within
seven years every political party in thc country had in
cluded in its platform an equal suffrage plank. Presi
dent Wilson had publicly appealed for the passage of
an amendment as "a vitally necessary war measure,"
and the amendment had been passed by both houses of
Congress and ratified by many states.
Her methods of calling the attention of the coun
try to the administration's responsibility were novel and
effective. She organized the first suffrage parade ever
held in Washington ; she organized a suffrage trans
continental trip, suffrage specials and suffrage picketing.
She took part in all these demonstrations, helping to
prepare even minute details and going with her fol
lowers to jail when the authorities attempted to put a
quietus on their activities. Miss Paul was sentenced to
terms ranging from ten days to six months. She went
on many hunger strikes while in jail and had to be
forcibly fed.
Miss Paul was so determined to put over suffrage
that in the early days of her Washington activities she
went without a new dress and noon lunches for three
years, devoting all her spare change to the work of
the cause.
When she does treat herself to a new dress it is
generally of a purple hue.
Her sole relaxation is sitting on a bench in his
torical Lafayette Park, opposite the White House,
where she divides her time between reading and feed
ing the pigeons, squirrels and birds which have come
to know her so well. They perch on her lap and
shoulders while she happily dips deep into her hand
bag for peanuts and other dainties dear to the ap
petites of little park pets.
The next big job ahead for Miss Paul is the stag
ing of a convention of the woman's party to decide up
on the policy of the future. The proceedings of that
convention will be of more than passing interest.
Foolish are those who think the suffragist ladies are
going to be content with the mere privilege of voting !
You can bet your shoes and victrola that it will be
no time until they will be demanding a fifty-fifty di
vision of all public offices from aldermen to cabinet
officers. And why shouldn't they?
The Tennessee ratification of the suffrage amend
ment leaves only one bothersome obstacle between
woman and the happy casting of a ballot telling her
age. Either the state legislatures will have to revise the
laws on that subject or permit the poll tax
collectors or registrars to use the following
scheme which any woman will readily admit
out-ouijas the ouija: Quietly hand a small
sheet of paper to the lady desiring to vote and
ask her to put down the number of the month
in which she was born, then to multiply it Dy
two, then add five, then to multiply it by 50.
than to add her age, then to subtract 365,
then to add 115, and then to hand back the re
sult. The two figures to the right will be her
age, and the remainder the month of her
birth. For example, the amount is 840 : She
is 40 years old, and was born in the eighth
month Ausrust. To such of the fair voters
as might have become a trifle rusty in the
annoying art of multiplying, adding and
subtracting, the election official could hand
this table of figures gently requesting her to indi
cate in which column or columns her age is contained,
and by adding together the figures at the top of the col
umns in which her age is found, the great secret would
be revealed without the lady uttering a single word.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1916-06-17/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=ANTHONY+B+SUSAN&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1917-03-10/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=Anthony+ANTHONY+B+SUSAN+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>IN the light of many of the protests of present-day suffragists and
anti-suffragists against what is commonly called “militancy,” it is
interesting to look back upon the long life of protest against injustice
lived by Susan B. Anthony before this opprobrious term was invented.
Susan B. Anthony did not realize her “militancy.” To her, to think
meant also to act, to translate the conclusions she had arrived at into
deeds. Throughout her whole life she lived consistently up to the maxim
she urged upon the women of her time: “Resistance to tyranny is
obedience to God.” In the face of newspaper criticism upon the action
of those they differentiated as “mild militants” and “physical militants”—
whatever those somewhat cryptic terms may mean —the forthright actions
of Susan Anthony seem revolutionary indeed.
Miss Anthony began her battle for equal rights for women at a time
when women were not only bound by law, but doubly bound by prejudice
and custom. After marriage a woman’s legal existence ceased. She was
unable to own property, to control her earnings, to make a will, to act as
the guardian of her own children. Her classification with idiots and
children under the law seemed to have created an enervating sub
servience in the whole attitude which the woman of 1848 brought to bear
upon life. It was at this time that Susan Anthony, the young school
teacher, a girl of 28, delegated to cook the huge Sunday dinners at which
her father was used to entertain the forward-looking men of his time,
was in the habit of lingering around the door, keeping an eye on jellies
and roasts and pies, to listen to Garrison, Pillsbury, Wendell Phillips and
Channing. In theory they all believed in what were then called “the
rights of women.” But it was this girl, toiling loyally in the huge hot
kitchen to cook their dinners, who determined to translate the great
sentiments of those abolitionists into action. Probably the seeds of the
“militancy” of Susan Anthony dated from those days.
Drawn first into the temperance movement, Susan Anthony very
speedily reached the conclusion that reform movements backed by
women were impossible of accomplishment for a class politically enslaved
under a party government able to reward or punish.
With political liberty as a goal, even as a girl she realized, however,
that women must first learn to stand upright, to speak aloud, and assert
their then theoretical equality. She realized, in short, that the very
psychology of woman must be changed before she could fight her own
battle.
But she hastened to put herself in the first ranks of American mili
tants when, a rigorously brought-up Quaker girl, she rose at a State
Teachers’ Convention in 1853 and asked to speak to a motion. It was the
first time in the history of such conventions, more than two-thirds com
posed of women, that a woman had had the temerity to lift her voice.
Led by the Chair, a formidable person “with buff vest, blue coat and
brass buttons,” the question raged for half an hour as to whether a
“female” should be allowed to speak in the convention. The memorable,
if brief, speech of the Quaker girl established a precedent in teachers’
conventions and pointed the way to the time, which Miss Anthony as a
pioneer helped to bring about, when a woman on a public platform ceased
to be a “sight” to ride miles to see.
Miss Anthony concerning these early meetings speaks of the “women
who drew away their skirts” that they might not touch such a bold
creature, and comments: “My heart was filled with grief and indignation
to see a minority, simply because they were men, presuming that in them
was vested all wisdom and knowledge; that they needed no aid, no
council from the majority. But what was most humiliating of all was to
look into the faces of those women and see that by far the larger portion
were perfectly satisfied with the position assigned them.”
It became the self-assigned task of this Quaker girl to arouse the sat
isfied women of this country. The small beginning of her task was the
winning of free speech for women. The old diatribes in the papers of
the time demonstrate the contumely and ridicule to which Miss Anthony
and the women who joined her were submitted.
From the time Miss Anthony as a girl abandoned teaching to devote
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
SUSAN B. ANTHONY , MILITANT
Mention the Maryland Suffrage News When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
her life to the woman’s battle for justice, her life became a series of
crusades, all leading toward the ultimate goal, the political recognition of
women. She entered the dress reform movement at the cost of personal
pam and misunderstanding, because at a time when the costume of the
period was especially hampering and injurious, this minor matter seemed
but one more detail of the whole battle. Her crusade in New York State
for the rights of married women, which finally came to a tardy victory,
marked the first tangible accomplishment of the woman’s rights move
ment in this country. After the enforced period of inactivity brought
about by the Givil War, the great dream of Miss Anthony’s life was
realized in a paper in which she hoped to epitomize the woman’s battle
in this country and waken the great rank and file to a realization of their
position.
This paper was called The Revolution, surely the most militant title
any woman’s paper has had before or since Miss Anthony’s time.
“Principle, not policy, justice not favors,” was the watchword with which
The Revolution was put out as the organ of “the National Party of New
America.” The struggle to maintain this revolutionary child and to pay
its final debt cost Miss Anthony bitter years of labor which no American
woman inveighing against the radical suffrage movement of today should
fail to remember. In the face of adverse criticism Miss Anthony kept
the defiant flag of her little paper flying for four years, before she re
turned to the suffrage movement to take up her work as a militant leader.
In 1872 Miss Anthony claimed the right to vote under the fourteenth
and fifteenth amendments of the United States Constitution, which pro
vide that no State shall abridge the privileges of citizens. Many leaders
had held that women were free to vote under these sections. Susan B.
Anthony and other leaders who shared her beliefs in defiance of the law
as interpreted put their convictions into practice. She voted in Rochester,
November 5, 1872, and was arrested two weeks later by a marshal of the
United States, with the 14 women who had voted with her. Even the
newspapers of her own time realized that she had thus defied tradition,
not for the sake of sensation, but as part of a life-long and consistent
campaign for women’s freedom.
During the subsequent trial of Susan B. Anthony, in which she de
fended herself for taking her right to vote as a citizen of the United
States, she found herself attacked as a “corruptionist” for trying to
“corrupt that justice under law which flows from trial by jury.” Though
the prosecution simply brought forward the fact that Miss Anthony had
voted, Associate Justice Ward Hunt instructed the jury to bring in a
verdict of guilty.
Refusing to sit down or to be silenced by that Court, Miss Anthony
protested against the judgment of the Court and refused to pay the fine,
declaring, “I shall earnestly and persistently continue to urge all women
to the practical recognition of the old Revolutionary doctrine, ‘Resistance
to tyranny is obedience to God.’ ”
It was but four years later at the great Centennial celebration of the
Declaration of Independence in Philadelphia, in which women were
barred from all participation, that Susan B. Anthony with her fellow
workers prepared a Woman’s Declaration of Rights, with which they
invaded Centennial Hall, where they had been forbidden the right of
public protest, and led by Miss Anthony, marched upon the great stage
into the presence of foreign rulers, the Vice-President and Government
officials, to register the protest of the women of the nation.
It was the spirit of rebellion in Susan B. Anthony that kept alive the
first demand for political freedom of women through many years. It is
this burning sense of injustice which she passed on to the suffragists of
today that is at once their hope and their greatest asset. When this spirit
of rebellion dies out, the woman’s movement in this country will be dead
indeed.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1940-02-11/ed-1/seq-13/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=Anthony+ANTHONY+B+SUSAN+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Susan B. Anthony
Will Bo Honored
At Ceremony Here
Four Congress Members to
Speak at Anniversary
Program Thursday
The 120th anniversary of the
birth of Susan B. Anthony, pioneer
for women’s rights, will be marked
by a ceremony in the crypt of the
Capitol at 8 p.m. Thursday in which
more than 40 women’s organizations
will participate.
Speakers will • include Senator
Gillette of Iowa and Representatives
Norton of New Jersey, Bender of
Ohio and Sumner of Illinois. Mrs.
Margaret Dugan Bodziak. Demo
cratic national committeewoman for
Delaware, will preside.
Representatives of the participat
ing organizations will lay wreaths at
the base of the statue of Miss An
thony and two other leaders of
women, Elizabeth Cady Stanton
and Lucretia Mott. The United
States Marine Band, under the lead
ership of William F. Santelmann,
will furnish music.
Throughout tne country cere
monies will be held in Miss An
thony's honor as part of the pro
gram of the Susan B. Anthony Me
morial Committee of the National
Woman's Party. Governors of many
States have set aside Thursday to
honor her.
Miss Anthony died in 1906 after
devoting her life to the cause of
women. She made many visits to
the Capitol to petition Congress for
the enfranchisement of women.
Lutherans to Initiate
War Relief Fund Drive
A luncheon meeting will be held
at 12:30 p.m. tomorrow at the Con
tinental Hotel to initiate a drive in
Washington Lutheran Churches to
raise part of a national fund of
$500,000 for war relief, sponsored
by American Lutherans. Dr. Oscar
C. Mees of Canton, Ohio, national
administrator for the drive, will
apeak.
All pastors of Washington Lu
theran Churches and prominent
Lutheran laymen have been invited
to attend the luncheon. Today will
be observed In Lutheran churches
as a day of prayer for all war suf
ferers.
Most of the $500,000 expected
from American Lutheran# Is to be
administered through the Lutheran
Church of Finland. Headquarters
for the campaign have been estab
lished in the Lutheran Church
House. 39 East Thirty-fifth street,
New York City.Susan B. Anthony's Idealism
To Guide New York Congress
One of the Trinity of *
U. S. Liberators Urged
Political Equality
By ANNE E. HENDLEY.
It is not detracting from the mem-,
ory of the Father of His Country, or
of the immortal Lincoln, to name
Susan B. Anthony as one of the
trinity of American liberators. She
fought for recognition of women, it
is true, but she battled also for the
rights of mankind.
Susan B. Anthony with dauntless
courage and indomitable w)U, with
vision and practical leadership,
wrung from the forces of might for
the members of her sex a place in
our Constitution as a protective
heritage of freedom and oppor
tunity. In doing so, she likewise
bequeathed to womanhood a great
responsibility. The final decision
may ultimately rest in women's
hands as to whether this civiliza
tion of ours will move to higher
levels or plunge into the abyss of
ruin. If the latter takes place, hu
manity will have to start the long
march upward all over again as it
has apparently done countless times
in history.
me men ana women oi America
Itve up to the spirit of Susan B.
Anthony we need have no fear for
the future of our Nation. The three
celebrated patriots, whose birthdays
wre are commemorating this month
were something more than mere
emancipators. They constituted a
great moral force and were veritable
dynamos of spiritual energy. The
driving power of their lives is felt
and drawn upon even to our day for
this generation is using their re
corded beliefs to strengthen our
faith in certain fundamentals that
form the basis of our national insti
tutions. The voice of a seer was
heard when our first President said:
“No people is more bound to ac
knowledge the Invisible Hand that
shapes the affairs of men than those
of these United States."
Each Step Appears Guided.
Every step by which we have ad
vanced to our present status of world
independence has been distinguished
by some providential token or
agency.. It was this spiritual insight
that gave elevation to the feeling,
thinking and planning of Washing:
ton, Lincoln and Susan B. Anthony.
Therefore, I hold up these three
leaders, not as idols to be worshipped,
but as ideals for the imitation of
aspiring souls in this crucial hour
in our local crusade for righteous
ness in the Bistrict of Columbia.
The sardonic mockery of a "Voteless
League of Women Voters” here will
not be perpetuated. The women's
organizations of America who are
fighting for political equity, have
made it clear that they will never
rest until this inconsistency is re
moved. When that day of victory
arrives, our tribute of honor to Susan
B. Anthony will be crowned and
perfected. Let us battle with all our
might to hasten the day!
I consider it one of the great priv
ileges of my life that, more than 40
y£ars_ago^j had the honor of per
TIRALLA, INC.
Upfiolaterart
4843 Mast. Aw. N.W. IM. 1001
/£•> v,'«- - . . U-— I
Any 3-Pc. Suite
RE-UPHOLSTERED
Choice of fine Quality Cotton Tapestries
and friezes. Near paddins. sprints re
built, new sprints In cushions, frames
tightened, woodwork rcfinished. Price
i:i 5 A 050
bolstered and
rerondi
tioned like ■
new.
Call EM ergon 1001
(/f^fcSr f°r Repregentative
with Sampleg.
GOLDENBERCS
Kh * * _YOUR THRIFT STOREHA. 5220
A SENSATIONAL SAVING—JUST
IN TIME FOR SPRING SEWING!
SEWING MACHINES
1.00
Down
And 1.00
a week pays
for it!
• Full Size Head • Air-Cooled Motor
o Apartment Size Walnut Finish Console Cabinet
A value you can hardly afford to overlook! This fine
electric sewer is made by the Domestic Co., famous for
more than 75 years for the fine quality of their machines.
Equipped with full-size head and many other worthwhile
sewing features.
Goldenberg’»—Main Floor—8th St. Entrance.
SUSAN B. ANTHONY.
sonal acquaintance and close associ
ation with Susan B. Anthony and I
caught a glimpse of the noble prin
ciples for which she lived. I have
seen her at meetings, presiding with
admirable poise under most distress
ing and distracting circumstances,
and hope in the near future a me
morial building will be erected in
Washington to this great woman
statesman who served her country
so valiantly, who impressed her per
sonality so indelibly upon the public
mind and fought so courageously
and persistently for a cause that
was not only inherently Just for
women,-but that stood for the moral
uplift of the whole human race. She
was the only one in history who gave
60 years of consecutive service for
a reform movement.
Miss Anthony reached her home
in Rochester on February 17. She
mounted the stairs to her room and
never came down again. To the last
moment of her life her brain re
mained clear and her faith un
shaken. In answer to a question
concerning a future life put to her
by Dr. Anna Shaw, who was in at
tendance at her bedside during the
last days of her earthly pilgrimage,
the frail sufferer replied, "I cannot
say, but I promise that if any one
there can help and influence those
who are left here, I will come to you.
If there is a conscious existence be
yond the grave, I do not see why I
should not desire to work there for
the sacred rights of women, and I
will always be where I am most
needed.”
Congress of Women to Meet.
One hundred years ago the first
international anti-slavery conven
tion was held in London, and organ
izations in every country were urged
to Bend delegates. The United States
selected eight women, who carried
the same credentials as the men.
To commemorate women’s advance
ment in the last century a congress
of women from all over the world
will be convened in New York City,
at the Astor Hotel, on November 25,
26 and 27, in 1940, with Carrie Chap
man Catt, at 81, as chairman. This
assemblage will emphasize achieve
ments of outstanding women in the
arts, sciences, business, education
and the professions, politics, religion
and social service that has advanced
welfare work along all lines of en
deavor. Economic problems will be
taken up and solved and the care of
children will be a major feature.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-11-12/ed-1/seq-13/#date1=1756&index=8&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1915-05-08/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1959-08-30/ed-1/seq-179/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1915-07-03/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>ON July 5, at a time when the men of this nation are rejoicing in the
fact that all men are ‘‘free and equal” in the United States, the
members of the Congressional Union in Maryland will celebrate in honor
of that great pioneer of the suffrage cause—Susan B. Anthony.
History tells us that at the Centennial celebration on July 4, 1876, in
the city of Philadelphia, the Declaration of Rights for Women was issued
by American suffragists. It reads: “Let the women of the whole land
unite with us in this Declaration,” “that the world may see that the
women of 1876 know and feel their political degradation no less than did
the men of 1776.” (From the Life and Work of Susan B. Anthony, by
Ida Husted Harper.)
“While the nation is buoyant with patriotism, and all hearts are attuned
to praise, it is with sorrow we come to strike the one discordant note on
this one-hundredth anniversary of our country’s birth. When subjects
of kings, emperors and czars from the Old World join in our national
jubilee, shall the women of the republic refuse to lay their hands with
benedictions on the nation’s head? Surveying America’s exposition, sur
passing in magnificence those of London, Paris and Vienna, shall we not
rejoice at the success of the youngest rival among the nations of the earth?
May not our hearts, in unison with all, swell with pride at our great
achievements as a people; our free speech, free press, free schools, free
church, and the rapid progress we have made in material wealth, trade,
commerce and the inventive arts? And we do rejoice in the success, thus
far, of our experiment of self-government. Our faith is firm and un
wavering in the broad principles of human rights proclaimed in 1776, not
only as abstract truths, but as the cornerstones of a republic. Yet we can
not forget, even in this glad hour, that while all men of every race, and
clime, and condition, have been invested with the full rights of citizenship
under our hospitable flag, all women still suffer the degradation of dis
franchisement.
“The history of our country the past hundred years has been a series of
assumptions and usurpations of power over woman, in direct opposition
to the principles of just government, acknowledged by the United States
as its foundation, which are:
“First—The natural rights of each individual.
“Second —The equality of these rights.
“Third—That rights not delegated are retained by the individual.
“Fourth—That no person can exercise the rights of others without
delegated authority.
“Fifth—That the non-use of rights does not destroy them.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
AMONG the young women of
Montgomery county who are
working for suffrage is Miss Lavinia
M. Engle of Forest Glen.
Miss Engle has always been an
ardent suffragist, taking an active
part in all debates on the subject dur
ing her high school and college years,
but her first practical work was done
under the auspices of the Just Gov
ernment League two years ago, when
she served as organizer for Montgom
ery county.
In February, 1914, she was ap
pointed Southern organizer for the
National under Mrs. Medill McCor
mick, and in that capacity worked in
several Southern States. Last sum
mer she conducted the suffrage shop
Mention the Maryland Suffrage News When Patronizing Our Advertisers.
“And for the violation of these fundamental principles of our Govern
ment we arraign our rulers on this Fourth day of July, 1876.”
“Here on this historic ground, under the shadow of Washington’s
statue, back of them the old Liberty bell proclaimed ‘Liberty to all the land
and the inhabitants thereof,’ they took their places, and to a listening, ap
plauding crowd, Miss Anthony read a copy of the Declaration.”—From
the Life and Work of Susan B. Anthony, by Ida Husted Harper.
The members of the Congressional Union feel that this is a fitting hour
to pay tribute to the life of Susan B. Anthony, whose work they are
endeavoring to continue by their efforts to have passed through Congress
the amendment drawn by Susan B. Anthony and introduced in 1875.
Promptly at 5 o’clock, at the sound of the bugle and the beat of the
drum, the members and friends of the Congressional Union will assemble
on Charles street, between Madison and Read streets, and there from a
handsomely decorated automobile will be read for the second time in the
history of this country The Woman’s Declaration of Independence.
The Declaration will be read by Miss Bertie M. Hall, who has often
impersonated the role of Susan B. Anthony.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1938-02-13/ed-1/seq-37/#date1=1756&index=13&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The month of February has given
to the world three great emancipa
tors, George Washington, who eman
cipated 3,000.000 Colonists from Eng
lish tyranny; Abraham Lincoln, who
emancipated 5,000,00C Negroes from
slavery, and Susan B. Anthony, who
led 50,000,000 women to political free
dom.
Washington and Lincoln had the
support of the ^rrt* and the sym
pathy of the people, and they worked
but a few years to accomplish their
aims. Susan B. Anthony worked for
60 years, meeting the bitterest oppo
sition from both men and women, al
ways facing the mob unfalteringly.
No woman with the exception of
Queen Victoria received greater rec
ognition or more editorial comments
from the whole world at the time of
her death than did Susan B. An
thony at the end of her 86 years of
life. It has been more than 32 years
since her death, and yet she alone
of the three has not been honored i
with a monument. It is fitting that
we, as a Nation, now recognize the
service of our pioneer woman leaders,
of whom Susan B. Anthony was the
acknowledged leader. The mother of
suffrage, she should therefore be the
first to be so honored.
Enchange With Greeley.
Miss Anthony, when speaking before
a group of university students, was
introduced to her audience as a
woman who possessed the brains of a
man. She did not like this charac
terization, for she had always main
tained that there was no* sex differ
ence in the matter of brain capacity.
She never lost an argument cm the
fundamentals of a question.
Shortly after the Civil War, Horace
Greeley was made chairman of the
constitutional convention called for
the purpose of revising the constitu
tion of the State of New York. Miss i
Anthony was chairman of a commit
tee of women who appeared before this
committee to ask that the word “male’’
be dropped from the constitution. In
the course of the hearing Mr. Greeley
said, “Miss Anthony, you know that
the ballot and the bullet go together;
If you are ready to vote, are you ready
to fight?" Miss Anthony’s reply was
Instant, “Yes, Mr. Greeley, just as you
fought in the late war, at the point
of a goose quill.”
New Worlds to Conquer.
In speaking of the long friendship
between Miss Anthony and herself,
Elizabeth Cady Stanton said; “I have
had no peace since we started on the
suffrage expedition in search of wom
an s place in the National Constitu
tion. One summer I sailed for Eu- I
rope, thinking that with the ocean
between us I would be <ree from
writing resolutions and addresses for
conventions; when, lo, to my utmost
surprise, I met Susan on the streets !
of London with a new light in her
eyes. Behold, there were new worlds
to conquer! Miss Anthony had de
cided to hold an international council
of women in Washington, D. C. We
returned to the scenes of our former
conflicts.”
The women of today owe a great debt
of gratitude to Susan B. Anthony and
these pioneer women. Married women
had no legal right to the wages which
they earned. No married woman could
own anything in her own right. No
W’oman could collect damages to her
person or to her reputation in a court
of law. Higher education was denied
her. She could not hold a public office
or vote. The last right was attempted
by Miss Anthony in Rochester. N, Y.,
election and she was arrested, tried,
convicted and fined. She replied to
the judge, “I will never pay one penny
of your unjust fine,” and she never
did.
Today the people of the civilized
world enjoy the right of franchise, ex
cept in the District of Columbia, where
neither men nor women have the right.
Susan B. Anthonys work Mother
of the Suffrage Movement” will not be
completed until equal representation
in Congress for the District of Colum
bia is accomplished. I quote from
Miss Anthony, “If you would have
your requests granted, your legislators
must know that you are a part of a
body of constituents who stand with
ballots in your hands.”
Triboat# From a Colleague..
I quote from a tribute paid to Susan
B. Anthony In 1897 by Frances E. Wil
lard. “From the age of adolescence my
love and loyalty have enveloped the
name of Susan B. Anthony. I look
upon her as that figure full of resource
and dignity which shall yet be en
shrined in the undying affection of the
whole republic; even as she has been
for a long time in the hearts of
thoughtful men and women. Others
have done nobly, and we count over
their names with devout remembrance
and gratitude; but Susan B Anth
ony, by reason of her self-sacrifice, her
lonely life, her disregard for position,
her concentration of purpose and good
will, have made for her a place on the
highest pedestal in the American pan
theon of great women.
•*We do not forget the untiring labors
which have carried her from youth to
age into every corner of the union and
over the seas. Many of us are cogni
sant of the facts of her personal kind
neas toward women in need who cher
Ish her as if she were a sister or a
mother. Blessed Susan B. Anthony.
MCept the homage of one woman you
have cheered and comforted and one
who rejoices to believe that the loving
friendship begun here, shall grow and
deepen in the bright light of that hap
pier world where you now dwell; a
world where there is no injustice and
where we have abundant reason to be
lieve, women shall stand in a place of
perfect equality.
Birthday Observed.
It is most gratifying to note«that for
»»ny years organizations and speakers
in Congress have been living up to the
resolution passed at the Victory Con
vention held in Chicago in 1920; vis.,
Tto observe the birthday anniversary
of Busan B. Anthony with loving re
membrance and gratitude ”
On February 15, 1937. the 117th an
niversary of the birth Of Miss Anthony,
th« Governors of 10 States, from Rhode
Island to California, and Hawaii, pro
claimed^ Sus&a B Anthony Day; and
Itis not too much to say, that in due
process of time, her birthday anniver
■efy will be celebrated around the
world.
the late Arthur Brisbane said
n*v,er was a nobler, more un
ttmsfo soldier of the human race. The
W(fld might well have wept, had that
chad born February 15, 1820, In
Atmms, Mass., been born a boy instead
•f Busan B. Anthony.”
We are fortunate in having with us J
•tit Carrie Chapman Oatt, Harriet ]
Tailor Upton, ajnet Richards, Jeanette
4* *
4
Jfe- . OHM**
A I
Rankin, Judge Mary O’Toole, Mary
Church Terrell and Adelaide Johnson,
the sculptress whose cunning hand
created the group of the pioneer
women now standing in the crypt of
the Nation’s Capitol.
May the present-day leaders carry
high the banner which those leaders
have laid down, ever to be inspired by
the work and accomplishments of these
noble women. Let every woman who
enjoys the freedom which Susan B.
Anthony helped to win, and every man
who rejoice* in the larger horizon of
the mothers of the race, pay loving
tribute to the great heart and daunt
less spirit of Susan B. Anthony.
Tagged Atom* Yield Data.
Tagged atoms show why some
diets fall to reduce. The body makes
fat no matter what is eaten and
bums most of it at once.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1915-05-01/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&index=16&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Susan B. Anthony amendment, will take place in Baltimore May 5 and 6.
The program includes business, social and political sessions.
A deputation has been arranged to visit Representative Charles J. Lin
thicum and Representative Charles P. Coady and make clear to them the
strength of the demand behind the Susan B. Anthony amendment. On
May 5 at 1.30 the delegation to Representative Linthicum will assemble
at the corner of Charles and P'ranklin streets and will march in procession
with bands and banners to Mr. Linthicum’s home, 705 St. Paul street.
After the interview the deputation will proceed to the Albion Hotel as
guests of Mrs. Ella Culbreth, and a business meeting, opening at 3 P. M.,
will be held. At this meeting a report will be given to all the members of
the Congressional Union of the result of the interview with Congressman
Linthicum.
Mrs. Donald R. Hooker, President of the Just Government League,
and chairman of the Finance Committee of the Union, will preside. She
will introduce Mrs. Gilson Gardner, of the Executive Committee of the
Congressional Union, who will speak on the history of federal work
for suffrage. The record of the Sixty-third Congress upon suffrage is to
be discussed by Miss Lucy Burns, Vice-Chairman of the Congressional
Union. Mrs. Edna S. Latimer will speak on “Party Responsibility in
Congress.” Mrs. Helena Hill Weed, daughter of Congressman-elect Hill
of Connecticut, will explain the two suffrage amendments now before the
Congress, and Miss Alice Paul, Chairman of the Congressional Union,
will lay before the convention a plan of work for Maryland.
At 1.30 on the following day a deputation will visit Congressman
Charles Coady and lay before him the demand in Maryland behind the
national suffrage amendment. The members of the delegation will meet
at Charles and Franklin streets. From there they will proceed in auto
mobiles gaily decorated in purple, gold and white, the colors of the Con
gressional Union, to Congressman Coady’s office, 10 South street. The
delegation will report this interview to the members of the Congressional
Union at 3 P. M., when they will assemble for the business session at the
home of Mrs. Summerfield Baldwin, 1006 North Charles street. The
presiding officer will be Mrs. J. William Funck, member of the Advisory
Council of the Congressional Union and President of the Maryland
Woman Suffrage Association. Mrs. M. E. Brooke of Chevy Chase will
present a constitution for the State of Maryland. After the constitution
has been decided upon officers for the State of Maryland will be elected
by the members.
Representatives will be chosen to attend the convention of women
voters to be held at San Francisco during the course of the Panama-Pacific
Exposition on September 14, 15 and 16.
On the evening of May 5 a one-act play by Miss Hazel Mac Kaye,
representing an incident in the life of Susan B. Anthony, will be presented
at Heptasophs’ Hall, Cathedral and Preston streets. The part of Susan
B. Anthony will be taken by Miss Bertie M. Hall; that of William Lloyd
Garrison by Mr. George W. Latimer; other parts will be taken by Miss
Marjorie Soper, Mrs. Blanche Veal, Miss Emma Harris Jamison and Mr.
M. Zurndorf. Dr. Cora Smith King, treasurer of the National Council of
Women Voters and an associate of the early leaders of the suffrage
movement, will speak on the life and personality of Susan B. Anthony.
On the evening of May 6 a reception will be given by the Congressional
sional Union of Maryland at the Hotel Emerson. Among the speakers will
be Mrs. Townsend Scott, Mrs. Harvey W. Wiley, Mrs. Florence Bayard
Hilles, chairman of the Congressional Union in Delaware, and the
Reverend Olympia Brown of Wisconsin.
Every suffragist in Maryland is invited and urged to attend all the
sessions of the Convention, especially the deputations to Messrs. Linthicum
and Coady. Automobiles have been chartered for the deputation to the
latter, and seats will be provided for all those who assemble at Charles
and Franklin streets at the appointed time.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060379/1915-11-13/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=17&rows=20&words=Anthony+B+Susan&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Susan+B.+Anthony&y=14&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MRS. SARA BARD FIELD, the plucky young woman who is motor
ing from San Francisco to Washington to present to Congress
resolutions and petitions urging the adoption of the resolution providing
for the Susan B. Anthony amendment to remove from the ballot the
qualifications of sex, has made an interesting report to Miss Alice Paul,
chairman of the Executive Committee of the Congressional Union.
Mrs. Field is stopping along the way to call upon public men and so
licit their support for the Federal amendment and make speeches to
crowds of people in behalf of woman suffrage.
“ ‘ln the enemy’s country’ is what the newspapers said when we got
to Missouri,” wrote Mrs. Field. “Missouri was the first non-suffrage
State we reached on the way from California. I would that all enemies
were of the same disposition as the Missourians. For a whole day and
night Kansas City, Mo., was rocked in the cradle of suffrage enthusiasm.
Great crowds attended our advent everywhere. We never spoke that
whole day from our noon meeting on the City Hall steps till the last late
street meeting at night that we did not have more people than our voices
could reach. As our simple auto procession passed down the street crowds
lined up to see it. The windows of every business house and office build
ing budded with a cluster of heads. Often there was applause and cheers.
Where these were lacking there was a peculiar sort of earnest curiosity.
And oh! those suffrage women! I would to high heaven every Western
voting woman who is making any sacrificial effort at all for national suf
frage could have seen those grateful women. ‘The greatest day for suf
frage Kansas City has ever seen,’ said some of the older suffrage work
ers. ‘How good of those Western women to come to our aid!’ At the
City Club meeting (which was packed) Frank P. Walsh predicted national
suffrage in 1916. There was good-fellowship over a suffrage dinner table
and earnest street meetings afterwards. Gravely interested crowds at
tended, and the whole city talked national suffrage for at least two days !
“Our great triumph in Des Moines was Senator Cummins’ unqualified
assertion of faith in our cause. He pledged himself to work for it by
voting and speaking both in public and private.
“The spirit of the lowa women, who themselves are in the midst of a
State campaign, is one to bring joy to all lovers of this movement. They
are not so absorbed in their immediate fight but what they can lift their
eyes to the larger suffrage field. They are too big for sectional interests
alone. They want suffrage nationally. They said: ‘lf we win next June,
how glad we shall be to get into this Western voting women’s movement
and stand back of the Susan B. Anthony amendment with our voting
support.’
A CENTER OF SUFFRAGE ACTIVITY
THOSE who think that the woman suffrage campaign is over are far
behind the times. They have another thought coming.
The failure of the State amendments in New York, New Jersey, Penn
sylvania and Massachusetts marks the real beginning of the climax of the
Congressional Union efforts for the Federal amendment to remove from
the ballot the qualification of sex. The leaders of the Union contend that
it is a waste of energy to try to amend all the State constitutions, and
urge all suffragists to join in their appeal to Congress.
MARYLAND SUFFRAGE NEWS
Mention the Maryland Suffrage New* When Patronizing Our Advertiser*.
Members of the Congressional Union assisted in the State campaigns,
but the Union’s principal energies for months have been to convince a
majority of the members of the present Congress to adopt the resolution
known as the Susan B. Anthony amendment. Now that the State cam
paigns are over, thousands of women will be available for the Washington
contest. The Congressional Union is approaching Congress by easy
stages; a definite plan is being followed. The part of the program not yet
carried out is to be executed in Washington when Congress convenes. A
national convention will be held December 6-13.
The program provides for: (1) A grand ovation to Mrs. Sara Bard
Field and Miss Frances Joliffee, the envoys from the Woman Voters’
Convention held in San Francisco last September, who are on their way
to Washington in a motor car; (2) the presentation of petitions signed by
thousands of persons —most of them voters —to President Wilson, who
has promised an audience to the envoys upon their arrival at the nation’s
capital December 6; (3) hearings before the Senate Committee on Woman
Suffrage and the House Judiciary Committee during the first week of
Congress, at which Mrs. Field, Miss Joliffe and others will testify; (4) a
mass-meeting at the Belasco Theater, Sunday, December 12, to hear
speeches from Senator Sutherland and Representative Mondell, who will
introduce the Susan B. Anthony amendment resolution in the Senate and
House, and from many prominent woman suffrage workers; (5) the
Susan B. Anthony Pageant, under the direction of Miss Hazel
Mac Kay, will be given at Convention Hall, Monday, December 13. Sev
eral elaborate dinner and social functions will be sandwiched in to add to
the gayety of the week.
The famous old mansion popularly known as the “Little White
House,” because it was used by several Vice-Presidents, will be the scene
of Congressional Union activities. The suffragists will be “at home” there
in December. From the White House the President can look out upon the
colors of the Congressional Union for Woman Suffrage—the purple, gold
and white, flying high against the sky—and would have little difficulty in
deciphering the blazing letters on their great banner strung out against
one of the balconies, “We demand an amendment to the United States
Constitution enfranchising women.”
President Wilson will see the envoys from the Women Voters’ Con
vention the same day Congress convenes. The hour has been fixed at 2
o’clock. The suffragists will present to the President resolutions urging
the passage of the Anthony amendment and a petition signed by more than
500,000 persons at the Panama-Pacific Exposition.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-president-grover-cleveland</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1885-03-04/ed-1/seq-1/#words=ROUND+TABLE+KNIGHTS</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The safe arrival
of President-elect Cleveland at an early hour
this morning gave great satisfaction, not be
cause any serious consequences were appre
hended, but because of afforded relief that
the presidential party had escaped
ALL POSSIBLE MISIIAPS
of travel aud accident and iniury of any
charracter. Alarmists spread the report that
cranks had threatened President Cleveland's
life, and the police authorities of New York
deemed their information sufficiently reliable
to warrant the closest surveillance of his
person and of suspecled individuals for the
past week or more. The police authorities of
Washington have been also on the gui vive for
the same length of time,and co-operated with
the New York and Albany officials in this be
half. Up toau early hour this morning when
the actual arrival of President-elect Cleve
land became known it was the opinion of
many shrewd persons that he had been
SMUGGLED INTO THE CITY
yesterday evening and quietly isolated in
private quarters. His declining to receive
any entertainment to-day from President
Arthur is commented upon as somewhat
anomalous, but the general opinion is that he
acted wisely and was influenced solely by
a desire not to occupy President Arthur's
time and attention at a period when the lat
ter was engrossed by immediate and pressing
business, further than to pay a visit of cere
mony. Altogether his demeanor to-day is
commended on all sides, and, notwithstand
ing the natural
FEELING OF PARTISAN POLITICS,
his political adversaries refer to him in words
of kindness. A Republican leader said
to the Globe correspondent to-day that the
question was whether Cleveland would boss
, tbe job or the job boss him, and it looked
! very much as if the first proposition would
obtain. There is not much cabinet talk to
night, the general impression being that the
slate heretofore announced of Bayard, Man
ning, Lamar, Vilas, Garland, Endicott and
Whitney will not be broken. There are those
who believe that the pressure to displace
Endicott and Whitney, which Is very strong,
will probably bave some effect Western
Democratic leaders complain that their
SECTION IIAS BEEN SLIGHTED
and that New York ought not to be awarded
two cabinet portfolios. The theory is ad
vanced that for the presentat least no change
will be made, but after the administration is
fairly established certain dispositions prefer
ably in supreme court retirements as well as
other Important offices, will enable President
Cleveland to even up things satisfactory re
specting the cabinet. His immediate friends
clamor to have him un train muled until he
can master the situation.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1886-06-03/ed-1/seq-1/#words=f+WED+IN+TH+WHITE+HOUSE</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Grover Cleveland and Frances
Folsom Made Man and Wife
SUNSHINE FOR THE BRIE
The President Whisks her Off to the
Mountains for the Honeymoon
The Old llama of President Gloriously
Decked with Flower to do Honor to tke
Young Bride A Democrnllo Crowd iln
en Outside tie Onlee Iloplaa for n
Ollmpie or Her Detail or Ike Ceremony
a4 Description of tke Dreesee by Cat
Dan lament Worried rllk a ninaA
DId leI e Ike lr ildenl Gift to
kis Bride Qneea Vletorln led Conerst
Dtnllon by Cable A Special Train Tnkee
tke President and kle Wife to I Cottage at
Deer Park In tie Maryland Allexkanles
ABnmaTOH Juno 2
z Other weddings thor
have ben at tbo White
k House but never be
I fore has n 1rosldont of
I tho United States been
aarrlod thero From
the very dawn of the
u wedding day tho city
r Boomed Mho to the ap
proaching event Lit
tle knots of idlora talked It over on tbo side
te
walks In front of hotels sodato matrons got
dped n they passed alone the streets and
bevies of laughing girls chatted nnd speculated
About It I there be truth In tho ancient
adage a happy bride will reign In tho White
House for thouch tho da opened with a Cray
and cheerless sky and shadows resting on the
earth yet n It Brow older the olomonta seem
ed to relent and little by little the sun forced
his rays through the unwilling olouds until
his broad beams fell In generous abundance on
tho eoft green sward of the trim park encom
passing the Whlto House bringing out In high
relief tho stately white columns of the time
tho
honorod home of Presidents sparkling on
spray of tho fountains and gilding the foliage
of the rand old trees
I i J1 s
vu wmt sons
Precisely at 5 oclock this morning a hand
some carriage drawn by two highstepping
sealbrown horses rolled out of the White
house stables with Albert Hawkins tho man
who ha boon coachman for seven Presidents
upon tho box The horse appeared to wondor
what had called them out at that extraordinary
hour But Hawkins was as wide awako n over
and had a pleasant good morning for Miss
Cleveland when she came out of tim White
House door She was watching for tho car
riage at the window of the reception room
when It came and In the quick emphatic way
she has she bolted oat of the front door and
was In the coach In as little time o It takos to
tel It Bhe was wearing a tailormade suit
that vn nearly the color of her hair and sho
turned up the collar of her Jacket n she found
the morning air was cold and damp Sinclair
the footman jumped upon tho box with Haw
kins and the carriage rolled out between the
Dlllars a rapidly oa It came and turned down
Pennsylvania avenue
As ho pulled up before the Baltimore and
Potomac depot the drlvor looked at his watch
and finding he hn < five minutes to spare
turned Up and down the streot while the lady
In tho snuffcolored suit who had come out at
dawn to meet her brothers sweetheart put her
bOld out of the carriage window and told
Hawkins not to BO too far uway Bbo had boen
to that same depot In that same carriage
shortly before midnight to receive her sister
and other friends and wan again illustrating
the devotion and determination that are her
strongest characteristics
It la said that sbo preferred to co to tho station
tion at that hour of the morning alono Thoro
was no reason lathe minds otherpeoplo why
the should but Ibo had a motive of her own
and people think she clioso this way of em
phasizing her sisterly Affaotlon for her broth
ers bride and her disavowal of tho feelings
that have been attributed to her concerning
this marriage At any rats she was there and
the bad ton or fifteen minutes to think over tho
situation which 1 will admit was unusual
Her Quick ear discerned the sound of an ap
proaching train and she called to Albert who
turned the noses of the finalbrown horses
down SlTth street a I ho wore driving away
from the station But the plan bad been pre
arranged and wna understood by those on the
car n well as the lady In tho carriage The
ear which was at the roar ot tho train wa de
tnchedbiiforo tbo locomotive entered tho depot
and shunted upon a spur that runs outside
along the street and which la usually occupied
by postal cars
The White Houso carriage pulled up along
side tho car when I stopped and two uniform
ed porters appeared promptly with their arms
full 01 bundles nnd travelling bogs Mr Ben
iolsom was the next to alight and bo too car
ried a heavy deck load of parcels which looked
very much a > if they bud come to hand after
the trunks had bon packed He toasod them
to Miss Cleveland who remained in the car
riage and then ho turned to assist Mrs Folsom
and the bride to audit
A CUY OnCETISO FOR MISS CLEVELAND
Tho latter wore a black silk so coverod with
let that It shimmered like nn armor and her
trim waist was covered with a jacket of gray
oashmorp Her bat was a white chip with
black bows and a ravens wing standing up co
duottUhly Bbo too had three or four Tittle
parcels In her bands and a scarlet umbrella
Her greeting to ls Hose as stio addrWs
ed the Presidents sister was quite gay and
neither by her appearance nor her manner did
Ihl show the effects of a nights travel and an
early awakening Mrs IoJsoin and her daugh
ter climbed Into tho carriage while cousin lion
actud as supercargo In stowlne awav tho freight
Lq side and outsldo the coach hero was I
good deal of merriment when he climbed Into
the carriage which was already pretty well
crowded and ho gave each of the porters u sli
ver dollar whim Miss Folsom gavo them a
smile a tho carriage drove away
It was not a brides morning A fog hung
over the city so densely as to conceal tho Capi
tol dome and moisture was oozing from the
Planks along the station Tbo air WAS murky
und heavy and the few people who truce about
at that hour took no notice of the Presidents
carriage 1 they recognized It
itwj a few minutes lUUr I whin the partr
rolled UD under the ort coohoro at the Whit
House and was thoro mot by halt a dozen
doorkeepers ana porter who assisted Sin
clair theifootman to carry the bundle Into the
vestibule They appeared to hue bon on tho
lookout and gave their future mistress a
hearty welcome Jerry the colored man who
has grown gray in tho service of Presidents
but still has tho air of a lord of high degree led
Mr Folsom nnd the ladles through tho wide
vestibule to the elevator but Miss Cleveland I
remained upon the portico to look after tho
baggage and give some orders to the coachman
Not mor than hal an hour pased when n bag
gage van arrived loaded with portentous trunks
roost of which woo of largo dimensions and
substantial appearance Some had a red cross
at either end while other boro tho letter F
of largo size in black paint The porters car
rung them in acted all thoy were heavy and
i
I
soil jruzimn CLITILIKD
the looks of the collection suggested thatsomo
body had coma to tho White Haute to stay
Tho President bad boon up for some minutes
when tho brldo arrived and was taking a cup
of coffee In the library as tho carriage drovo up
The ladles and Mr Folsom sat down with him
and coffeo with biscuit was ordered for fIve
While the party wore chatting briskly r
Hot came In from her room which adjoins the
library kissed the bride on both cheeks and
drew a chair close to her
THE LADIES INSPECT TUE WEDDING OOWN
The events of yesterday and the plans for to
day were familiarly dlicussod for a while and
than the brldo was led away to what Is known
as tho Garfield chamber which Miss Nelson oc
cupied lost night A breakfast of shad and
chops and cucumbers was served at 8 oclock
nnd after that the brldo disappeared and was
not visible until luncheon at 2 Those who in
quired for her were told that sho was busy un
packing and as abe has no maid ono of tho
servants of tho house assisted her The poem
In Ivory satin was shaken out and carefully In
snooted by all of the ladles of tho family and
of the other wero commented
some te gowns upon
ns thoy were taken out of tho trunk and Mra
Folsom or tho owner gave a history of each
There was a good deal of amusement over the
published descriptions of the trousseau which
the ladles say are not at all accurate and are
based upon puro guess work In nearly every
instance After luncheon and a halt hours talk
with the Prcsldont Miss Folsom wont to her
room again and lay down for a nap while her
mother shifted into a single trunk such gar
ments as she would need for a weeks journey
AT THE WHITE HOUSE DURING THE DAT
Tho White House was closed to visitors all
day and the only Senator who had the nerve
and persistence to demand and obtain admit
tanco was Van Wick of Nebraska but he did
not see tho President Ho got as far n Col
Laments room and then ho was invited to call
again Secretary Lamar Assistant Secretary
Falrchlld and Assistant Secretary Porter of
the State Department tho only otherofll
clal visitors and they found some troublo lu
getting In The President was reported by the
attendants t bo at his desk at work as usual
and there were evidences of his closing up af
fairs for a vacation At the Cabinet meeting
yesterday no reference was made to his in
tended absence from tho city and one of the
Secretaries said that the regular Cabinet meet
ing would be bold tomorrow a usual but
these little remarks wore pretty well under
stood a intended to throw inquisitive corre
spondents off tho scent
TIIE PAESON TAKES THE BRIDES INSTRUCTIONS
About 12 oclock a rustylooking coup drove
up to tho front door and a little man in black
broadcloth and 1 clerical cravat alighted That
bo was expected appeared certain be
cause the door opened promptly to him and no
questions wero asked Ho was shown into tbo
Duo loom whore the ceremony was to take 1
place and went about poking his nose into tbo
banks of flowers until be was asked up stairs
to meet tho girl ho bad hen invited to join In
tho of the United
holy Wedlock to President Unied
States Tho plan of the ceremony was ar
ranged and the brldo who seemed to be fa
miliar with such matters Indicated the form
ula that she preferred
Dr Bunderland went away just as the clock
was striking one Tho Her Mr Cleveland tho
Presidents brother camo out with Mr Sunder
land and taking the official carriage started
for a drive
About 1 oclock law partner Blssell who
got In this morning and Is stopping at the Ar
lington rode over to the White Houso which
la only one block away with as much ceremony
uw unu ia w a 1119111
a i he was going to be married himself He
wore a natty boutonnire and bamboo cane
and carried In his hand a package which was
addressed to Hon drover Cleveland and
came from Tiffanys I is supposed to have
contained tho Presidents marriage gift to his
brldo
THE mESIPENT DUST WIT OFFICIAL PAPErs
Just before luncheon time the President loft
his library whom bo had boon engaged all tho
morning and went with a largo package of papers
morlol
occuplod by
pert In his hand Into tho room
tho clerks He cave some Instructions to ono
of tho clerks as to the disposition t bo made of
the papers and then wont to the dining room
wherd the rest of tho family had preceded him
Ho did not look or act like 1 man who was ou
the odlo 01 matrimony lie was as undisturbed
as I bo woro to meet a delegation of olTlco
seekers Instead Ille wan freshly shaven by his
own hands for he employs no barber and hn
wore a smite that was uncommonly broad for
him About half past 2 he and law partner Diesel
cot Intf the victoria and stnrtud off for a drive
The President tore a black frock coat buttoned
closely actors his broast a good deal of super
fluous shirt collar and a check scarf After an
absence of about an hour the party returned
lacking my comfortable and contented and I
wsj Jjaiaed tint the > FiMldoat toad driven BJ >
soil out to see his now country place
con LAXtONT BUYS A LICIN8B Jon A DOLLAH
About 1 oclock this morning Col Lamont
Jumped into tho official carriage which bad
boon kept standing at the White Houso door
and told tho coachman t drive t tho City
Hall Ho hurried Into tbo office of the Clerk
of tho District Supreme Court and there ob
tained upon tho payment of a foe of 1 a
document which reads as follows
J any Jflnlito eftAi eetpft Authorliti 1 Ctltlratt Mar
rioett In IAe Dlttrlct ot CVIumKa cr Unj
You are hereby Hoemed to tolemnlse the rltee ot mar
dig between Orover Cleveland ot Buffalo N T and
Prank C Foltom ot Buffalo N Y It yea find unlawful
Impediment thereto and having 1 done you are com
manded 1 appear In the Clerks office ot the Supreme
Court of said District and certify the same
Wltnes my hand and the seal of laid court this
second day ot Jane 188 I J hIde Clerk I
To this license is appended a form of return
to b flllod out by tho officiating minister
follows 1
I minister of Church In here I
by certify that by authority ot 1 license of the lame I I
tenor ai the foregoing I solemnized the marriage of the
partIes ford on the day of 18 at
In the District of Columbia
With this very Important document which
cost the President ono silver dollar buttoned
up closely In his broatt pookotCoL Lamont bur
nod to his carriage and drove back t the Ex
ecutive Mansion n if somebody was waiting
for him there
Another Important commission executed by
Col Lament for his best friend was to send
over to Treasurer Jordan for a crisp noW 1100
United Stats note which was tucked away In
to rightband pookot of tho Presidents waist
coatTUB
TUB PRESIDENTS WEDDING SUIT Aitnrvica
Express wagons wero arriving at tho White
House all day and leaving all sorts of package
thoro big and little Bomo of them woro ad
dressed tho President of the United States
others t drover Cleveland more to Miss
Frank 0 Folsom and several to Col Lamont
Ono of them dono up very tidily was directed
to Mrs Grover Cleveland and tho express
agent Inquired of tho doorkoopor it such 1 lady
was stopping there
Sho is expected about 7 oclock tonight
was tho reply
A largo number of presents woro received by
Miss Folsom while sho was In Now York and
those worD the packages that wore brought
ovor with her In tho special car Bo tar no ono
outaldo 01 tho family has boon allowed to In
spect them and it is said that only a tow will
be publicly shown
PInard the Now York caterer arrived by tho
oclock train and had n wagon load of sup
plies for tho suppor with him Including the
wedding cake Ho had charge of tho arrange
ment of tbo table but tho supper was served
under the direction of tho regular steward
About oclocka packago was delivered with
tho mark of I Fifth avenue tailor upon It and
is supposed to have sheltered the Presidents
wedding suit which was ordered by Col La
mont when ho wont to moot Miss Folsom and
was fitted to tho President on Decoration Day
CONOIIATULATIONS BY THE BUSHEL I
The official telegraph operatorwas kept busy I
all any receiving despatches of congratulation
which came from all parts of the country
Noavly every man who hopes or expects to got
an office undor tho President took advantage
of the occasion t tender his compliments
and beat wishes t the brldo and tho first
President who was ever married in the
White Houio and Mr Cleveland will doubtless
be reminded of these messages In the futuro
An unusual number of letters were received
Thoro wore some curious compositions among
thorn Every crank who had a shoot of paper
and a pen used them upon tho President
Thoro worD many kindly notes of congratula
tion and some letters of wellmoant advice
nono of which the President will over BOO un
less tho time shall come when ho has nothing
else to do
1 B and Mrs Hayes and Mrs Grant sent
congratulatory telegrams and cablegrams
wore received from Euroue but their contents
or the source from which thoy came could not
b learned They are understood to be from
United States Ministers and friends abroad
and Mr bayard has somo official congratula
tions from potentates In other parts of the
world but Is shyer that the potentates are
about making them public
AttorneyGeneral Garland is usually at his
office by 8 oclock In tho morning an hour be
fore any of his clerks except his private sec
retary and ho says that during this hour ho
does the best work of tho day but this morning
ho did not got down until after 10 and the
clerks wondered what had happened to him
for such tardiness bad occurred elnoo he en
tered the Cabinet I was discovered finally
that he and his mother Mrs Hubbard had
been in search of a wedding present nod
searched the stores In town until they finally
found ono to suit them bought and paid for It
and ordered it sent to the Executive Mansion
with a card bearing the inscription With
the compliments of tho AttorneyGeneral and
Mrs Ilubbard
SCENES OUTSIDE AT THE WZDDlNd
I was a pretty warm evening for 0 wed
ding and in the White House with ev
ery chandelier ablaze tho shutters tight
ly closed and the perfume ot the mil
lion flowers weighing down the air tho
mercury lingered around the 110th degree on
the official weather gauge I was considered
rather clever when first suggested that Big
nat Service flaxen had ordered the weather to
suit but tho joke became somewhat tiresome
when U had been repeated by halt the popula
tion People took liberties with tho occasion
and other jests wore passed nrouud for nobody
spoke of other topics than the wedding Tho
children talked of It on their way to school and
when thoy started homeward went through the
White House grounds hoping to catch a
cllmpso of the Presidents brldo or some of her
belongings The Senators and Congressmen
discussed It In tho cloak rooms and no subject
since the assassination of Garfield has so con
cerned the public mind
The fog of the moraine cleared away at an
early hour nnd the day became as bright and
sunny as a lovers smile a little too warm for
busy people but those who live a time In Wash
ington catch tho methods of the place and be
come deliberate</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1886-06-25/ed-1/seq-4/#words=VETO+PRESIDENT</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>President Cleveland is entitled to the
appellation of the veto president. His
record as the vetoer of bills is unsurpassed,
although lie has only completed a little
more than fifteen months of his term. It
has been urged that the veto power reposed
In the president is a dangerous feature in
our organic law, as it places too much power
in the hands of one man, which if used ar
bitrarily could be exercised to the detriment
of the public interests. • It is true that con
gress has the right by a two-thirds vote to
pass a bill over the president's veto and
that this fact to a certain extent answers
the objection to the veto power. At the
came time there are Instances, such as
the rush of business immediately pre
ceding the adjournment of congress, when
it would be next to impossible to get
a vote on a vetoed bill, and thus
the president would be master of the situa
tion. However objectionable the veto
feature may be, it cannot be urged against
President Cleveland that he has abused
this power, notwithstanding the frequency
•with which he has been called upon to use
it. The people are with him in this mat
ter. The public treasury has been
tapped so often, and so nearly ex
hausted by the multiplicity of private bills
which have squeezed through congress by
one crook or another that the country is
gratified to see a check placed on this ex
travagant system of legislation. As long as
the president continues to exercise the same
judicious discrimination that he has shown
tip to this time he can keep right along with
the veto racket. Twenty-nine vetoes in one
day is a good record, but if it takes 229 per
day to check congressional extravagauce
Y e hope the president will pile them in.
A TIMELY REBUKE.
The grand jury of Hennepin county saw
fit to give the Minneapolis daily newspa
pers a very appropriate lecture for their
reprehensible conduct in publishing testi
mony relating to matters which were the
subject of secret investigation by that body.
The Minneapolis newspapers were probably
led into this indiscreet action by their parti
san zeal and the hope of trump
ing up a case against the Demo
cratic administration of that city,
As is well understood in newspaper circles,
there are limits to legitimate journalism,
and the publication of secrets which belong
to a grand jury is not considered in the line
of journalistic enterprise. A newspaper,
like an individual, should hold the public
interest of paramount importance to
individual interests or private con
siderations. We are sorry that our
Minneapolis contemporaries were so blinded
by their partisan zeal as to grossly violate
all the rules and established customs of
journalism, and while we commiserate their
misguided judgment, still we feel that they
richly deserved the severe rebuke which the
Hennepin county gland jury grave them.
Our advice to them is to go and sin no
more.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86064205/1887-02-17/ed-1/seq-4/#words=CLEVELANDS+LAST+VETO</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>CLEVELAND LAST VETO
  He
Returns the Drouth Belief Seed
Bill to the House Without His
Approval Thereto
II Senators and Representatives Wish
Aid the Texas Farmers They Can
Do so Keadlly
VETOED
Washington Feb 1C The President
has vetoed the bill appropriating 310000
for the distribution of seeds to the drouth
stricken counties of Texas
WHAT THE TRESIDENT SAYS
Washington Feb 1C The following
is the message of the President vetoing
the bill for the distribution of seeds in
Texas
To the House of Representatives
I return without my approval House
bill No 1020S entitled An act to enable
the Commissioner of Agriculture to make
a special distribution of seeds in the
drouth stricken counties of Texas
and making an appropriation tnerefor
It Is represented that a long continued
and extensive drouth has existed in cer
tain portions of the state of Texasresult
ing in the failure of crops and consequent
distress and destitution Though there
has been some difference in the state
ments concerning the extent of the peo
ples needs in the localities thus affected
there seems to be no doubt that there has
existed a condition calling for relief and
1 am willing to believe that notwithstand
Inc the aid already furnished the dona
tion of seed grain to the farmers located
in this region to enable them to
put in new crops would serve to avert
a continuance of an unfortunate
blight and yet I feel obliged to withhold
my approval of the plan proposed by this
bill to indulge a benevolent and
charitable sentiment through the ap
propration of public funds
for that purpose I can find
no warrant for such an appropriation in
the constitution and I do not believe the
power and duty of the general govern
ment ought to be extended to the relief
of individual suffering which is in no
manner relate I to the public service or
benefit
The prevalent tendency to disregard
the limited mission of this power and
duty should I think be steadfastly re
sisted to the end that the lesson should
be constantly entorced that the people
should support the government and the
government should not support
the people The friendliness of
the charity of our country can always be
relied upon to relieve their fellow citizens
in misfortune This Tias been repeat
edly and quite lately demonstrated
Federal aid in such cases en
courages the expectation of paternal
care on the part of the government and
weakens the sturdiness of our national
character while it prevents the indul
gence among our people of that
kindly sentiment and conduct
which strengthens the bonds of
common brotherhood It is within my
personal knowledge that individual
aid has to some extent already been ex
tended to the sufferers mentioned
in this bill The failure of
the proposed appropriation of 510000
additional to meet their remaining
wants will not necessarily result In con
tinued distress if the emergency is made
known to the people of the conntry and
it is here suggested The Commis
sioner of Agriculture is annually
directed to expend a large sura of
money for the purpose of propagation
and distribution ef seeds and other
things of this description twothirds
of which are upon the request of Sen
ators Representatives and Delegates in
Congresssupplied to them fordistribution
among their constituents The appro
priation of the current year for this pur
pose is 100000 and it will probably be
no less in the appropriation for the ensu
ing year I understand that a large quan
tity of the gram has been furnished for
such distribution and it is supposed that
this free apportionment among their
neighbors is a privilege which was waived
by our Senators and Representatives
If sullicient of them should request
the Commissioner of Agriculture to
send their shares of grain thus allowed
them to the suffering farmers of Texas
they might be enabled to sow their crops
The constituents for whom in theory this
grain is intended could well bear tem
porary deprivation and the donors would
experience the satisfaction of the attend
ing deeds of charity
Signedj Grover Cleveland</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89066489/1892-11-16/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=CLEVELAND+GROVER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1908-12-06/ed-1/seq-15/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1948-04-04/ed-1/seq-114/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1913-02-21/ed-1/seq-27/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86090439/1892-12-22/ed-1/seq-24/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=CLEVELAND+GROVER&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1913-01-14/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1954-05-02/ed-1/seq-124/#date1=1756&index=8&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1925-03-04/ed-1/seq-43/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-01-03/ed-1/seq-11/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1915-05-23/ed-1/seq-15/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20&words=Cleveland+Grover&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Grover+Cleveland&y=18&x=20&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ralph-bunche</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn79000083/1947-12-20/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1947&index=2&rows=20&words=Bunche&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1947&proxtext=bunche+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Secretary Gen
eral Trygve Lie, was revealed
here this week, was the man be
hind the choosing of Dr. Ralph J.
Bunche to head the U. N. Sec
retarist which will prepare the
Holy Land for parition.
Dr. Bunche, 43 year old Calif
ornia educated Negro, impresses
Lie by his work last Summer in
Palestine as a leading adviser to
the U. N. Special Committee on
Palestine.
Bunche as a correspondent for
the Chicago Daily News Foreign
Service said here this week, is
“one of the ablest, most likable
and most experienced man in the
United Nations’ Secretariat”. The
job he was picked for, which will
take almost a year, is “just a
bout the toughest job on the in
ternation horizan”, the same cor
respondent said.
Bunche must help lead Pales
tine Jews and Arabs into state
hood by October 1.
Director of the U. N. Division
of Trusteeships, Phi Beta Kappa
fro mUCLA with a Doctor of Phil
osophy from Harvard, Bunche is
43 years old, was born in Detroit.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78001213/1949-03-11/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1949&sort=date&date2=1949&words=Bunche&language=&sequence=0&lccn=&index=5&state=&rows=20&ortext=&proxtext=bunche+&year=&phrasetext=&andtext=&proxValue=&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=14</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ralph Bunche Is the Hero of the Day
By Boris Smolar
(Copyright, 1949, Jawiah Telegraphic
Agency, Inc.)
U.N. NOTES: A feeling of
great pride prevails in the ranks
of United Nations officialdom in
■ connection with
the success of
U.N. mediation
between Israel
and Egypt^^
in the United
Nations predict
that Dr. Ralph
mediator, will
be the recipient
Smolar °J the p . Nob . el
Peace Prize, in
recognition of his achievement.
At the same time it is reported
in American business circles that
Dr. Bunche may be appointed
American ambassador to Moscow’.
. . This would be the first time
in American history that a Negro
would be appointed to such a high
post. . . .
No one in the United Nations
doubts now that Israel will soon
be admitted to U.N. membership.
. . This is now considered a mat
ter of great importance not only
to Israel, but also to Britain and
the United States. . . .
It is obvious to British diplo
mats that Bevin’s talks in Lon
don for the formation of an East
ern Mediterranean alliance, to be
linked with the North Atlantic al
liance, will never be effective with
out Israel’s participation. ... It is
realized that Israel is now a major
power among the Eastern Mediter
ranean countries, and both Britain
and the United States want all
these countries to be a members
of the United Nations. . . .
On the other hand, it is also
taken into consideration that Is
rael will try to maintain a neutral
attiude in any manipulations be
tween the Western Nations and
the Soviet Bloc. ... In its effort
to maintain neutrality, Israel may
prefer to get economic and fi
nancial assistance through the
United Nations rather than direct
-11 ly from the Big Powers, it is be-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92051343/1949-05-14/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1949&index=1&rows=20&words=Bunche&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1949&proxtext=bunche+&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ralph Bunche told THE NEW ENGLAND BULLETIN
in an exclusive interview here last week.
The suave, handsome statesman, who recently returned to the
United States from his tough assignment of mediating the Palestine
situation, spoke with grave sincerity of the necessity for eliminating
exploitaton of colonial peoples.
"We cannot lay a firm foundation for peace in the world unless
the international community takes great steps toward eliminating
colonial problems, imperialism, rivalries over colonial areas and the
use of colonial people as pawns," he emphasized.
Twenty years of study and work
in the area of: colonial problems
has made Dr. Bunche an expert. It
is his first love in the thrilling,
important field of dealing with
world problems. His assignment in
Palestine, he looks upon as a
"strange interlude."
Rumors have been persistent that
the brilliant Dr. Bunche would ac
cept an offer to become an As
sistant Secretary of State in the
Truman Administration. The internationally-famed
diplomat who
gave the world an example of sterl
ing courage and resolution when
he took over critical negotiations
in Palestine after the assassina
tion of Count Bernadotte, indicated
that he would like to continue his
work with the United Nations.
In the event he were offered a
post in the National Government,
Dr. Bunche explained, he would
consider it a great honor. However,
he indicated his first interest lies
and would probably remain in the
colonial trusteeship problem.
"As a father of three children,
I have a very, special interest in
what kind of world ours is going
to be," he continued.
"Unpleasant Fan Mail"
Interesting sidelight on what
went on behind the scenes at Pal
estine was revealed when we asked
Dr. Bunche for some particulars
about unpleasantnesses he had en
countered early in the negotiations.
We had in mind his being charged
with anti-Jewish prejudice.
"I never had any trouble with
the people of Palestine," he an
swered calmly. "I received a num
ber of nasty letters last fall and
rierht throuerh December. They all
came from New York. I never had
the Palestine assignment one of
the most complicated in the his
tory of mediation is that there were
actually eight parties involved,
rather than two or three.
Dr. Bunche explained that his
dealings were with the Jewish
state of Israel and the even Arab
states all of whom are independ
ent and have different policies and
attitudes.
Presently, he is involved on the
last leg of Palestine problem
that; of negotiations with Syria.
Every morning he leaves his beautifully-appointed
home in the UN
development here and goes to his
office at UN. His life these days
is one merry-go-round of newspa
permen, photographer, well-wishers,
friends, folks who want to ap
pear on this program or that. He
hasn't had a vacation since 1941,
going from war work to OSS, the
State Department and finally, the
UN.
He's A Tired Man
Although the Palestine Mediator
is fit and looking his capably alert
self, he is a very tired man. He
has been under a tremendous
strain, not only mental, but, in
actual physical danger a fact
which he shrugs off.
He's' looking forward to the con
clusion of the Syrian negotiations
so that he can take a long, long
vacation. He says his plan for a
vacation is a vacation without plan.
"I just want to pick up and leave
with the family, go anywhere I
want to go, do anything I want
to do fishing, hunting. J Just re
lax. No schedule or routine."
Certainly, , he won't want to see
any newspaper folk for a long
time. It is hard to understand how
he can be so gracious. The metro
politan dailies, wire services and
representatives of Negro papers
came xroxii ew x ux ' A" are constantly at his heels. Harpers
an unpleasant note from an Arab , nnll- ÌT1AS flrft
exhaustive features on him, trail
ing him about daily.
He finds it necessary to stick
- v ' : "
' ' Sir
tote
HISTORIC DOCUMENTS are these which Dr. Ralph Bunche is displaying to Bulletin staffer
Alfred A. Duckett during a recent interview at the Bunche's beautiful home in the United Nations de
velopment. The documents are bound copies of original armistice agreements which brought peace to
embattled Palestine. (Bulletin Photo by Arnold DeMiile.)
or Jew over there. All my un
pleasant fan mail was from here."
He smiled as he said this.
"Since I was dealing with the
Jews and Arabs there in Palestine
and only with them, the observa
tions of people in New York who
did not and could not understand
had no bearing on my actions or
decisions," he added. "What was
being said here didn't bother me."
Dr. Bunche is happy, however,
that, in light of his handling of
the situation, those who had ac
cused him of anti-Semitism are left
without a leg to stand on.
One of the factors which made
pretty close to the city. The other
night he was on his way into the
National Broadcasting studios when
he received a message that he was
urgently needed back at UN due
to important developments in Pal
estine. Its pretty much of a rough
life for him.
We wondered what he thought
about Mr. Robeson's Paris state
ment. He said it was "an absurd
sia could never be wrong, which
is, of course, equally absurd.
Interested observer during the
interview was pretty Mrs. Bunche.
Five-year-old Ralph, a handsome,
active and quite precocious young
ster, flitted in and out the room
until Father Bunche diplomatically
persuaded him it was bedtime.
Objects To $50 Dinner
Just before we left, we had a
splendid example of the human
Varmness of this man who has
been called by The New York
Times "the outstanding Negro in
the world.
A group of top-level socialities
had planned a Waldorf-Astoria
dinner in his honor a benefit for
the National Conference of Chris
tians and Jews. Tickets were be
ing sold at $50 a plate. - He had
asked that the dinner be cancelled
because, as he put it:
"Most of my life I've been a
professor and in government serv
ice. I object to the principal of a
fifty-dollar dinner because most of
my friends could not afford to at
tend." It was a forthright remark, prov
ing that an able man who has made
headlines around the world, who is
one of the foremost factors in the
news events of the day and who
handled a crucial world situation
with great skill integrity and fi
nesse is still the Ralph Bunche so
many of his friends knew and ad
mired before he became the cynos-
his statement, reverting to the pos
sible offer of a high government
job.
"I have a great deal of faith in
the United Nations. There is where
I feel the charter for world peace
may be written. If I were to leave
UN, I think I should likely want
to return to my profession that
of teaching."
Ralph Bunche ,one of the ten
most important world citizens to
day has never stopped teaching.
Axis vuuxcigt; iiu puwer ou neep
unswervingly to a principal have
taught the world of today a les
son which that world or students
'forget.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84021917/1950-09-29/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1950&index=1&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1950&proxtext=ralph+bunche&y=7&x=14&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Dr. Ralph Bunche
last Friday said the 1950 Nobel Peace Prize will inspire
him to “continue my efforts in the great cause of world
peace.”
Announcement of the award of the 1950 Nobel Peace
Prize to Dr. Bunche, American statesman and educator,
was ’announced in Oslo, Norway
last Friday by the Nobel Prize
Committee of the Norwegian Par
liament.
The 46-year old United Nations
official, eleventh American and
first colored person to be so hon
ored, received the award in recog
nition of his work as mediator in
the Arab-Israeli war in Palestine.
Dr. Bunche will receive the
award in Oslo, December 19, an
niversary of the death of Alfred
Nobel, inventor of dynamite.
The United Nations official paus
ed in the midst of a deluge of
congratulations to issue a state
ment, in which he said:
“I received the news with deep
humility, for I, more than anyone,
recognize the extent to which his
peace efforts in the Near East
flowed from the strength of the
United Nations.
“In these crucial times,” he
added, “when the future of all
mankind hangs fatefully in the
NEGRO MARRIES WHITE
WEALTHY DIVORCEE
DETROIT (NNPA) The long
rumored marriage of Mrs. Elea
nor Sydnam Stahl, 47, wealthy
white Detroit society woman and
divorcee, and William Tibbs, 26,
year old colored man, was con
firmed last Thursday by the couple
in an interview at their suite in
the Gotham Hotel.
Both vowed they are “complet
ely happy” and insisted “it will
work out all right.”
They sat holding hands through
SPECIAL NOTICE
Dear Readers:
In view of the fact that the cost of printing, and
other phases of publishing have been increased, we
wish to announce that the price of the Arizona Sun
will be raised beginning next issue from 5c to 10c a
copy. Yearly subscriptions will be raised from $2 to
$3 a year; 6 months, $1.50.
For eight long years, the staff, including the boys
who bring your paper to your door, have not had
a raise, despite the fact that everything else under
the sun have increased in price.
To justify this increase in price, we are trying to
give you a better paper in every respect. The Sun
will also hit the streets and newsstands on Thursday
instead of Friday.
FIVE CENTS PER COPY
balance, it is high privilege to be
associated with the work of the
UN, man’s sole hope for peace.”
Dr. Bunche gave credit to the
UN, Count Folke Bernadotte and
to the UN observers and civil serv
ants for the success of the Pales
tine mediation.
“I was in Palestine as an offi
cial of the United Nations,” he
said, “for five months I was as
sistant of Count Folke Bernadotte,
the great and courageous man who
gave his life in the determined
effort to bring peace to Palestine.
It was Count Bernadotte who
achieved the first truce in Pales
tine, and thereby laid the essential
foundations for the armistice
agreements.”
“In all of my efforts I was
strongly backed by the Security
Council of the United Nations,” he
continued. “Moreover, I had con
(Continued on page 3)
out the interview, and the bride,
who has two grown children,
gazed frequently and proudly at
her unusual engagement ring
two pearls surrounded by dia
monds. One pearl is white, the
other black.
“We couldn’t think of any bet
ter ring than this,” she said.
They were married August 26
at the Shiloh Baptist Church in
Tuckahoe, New York, with Tibbs’</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84021917/1963-02-07/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1963&index=6&rows=20&words=BUNCHE+Bunche+RALPH+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=ralph+bunche&y=10&x=13&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Dr. Bunche was picketed when
Bunche Answers Critics
Secretary Defends UN Actions
Dr. Bunche, speaking to a full
house at the Temple Forum series
last Sunday evening, February 3,
at Temple Beth Israel, 11th Ave
nue and East Osborn Road, told
an eager audience that he would
not mince words.
After joking about his being
picketed for the first time at an
airport, he admitted that pickets
are general the world over and
are basically well-intentioned but
ill-informed.
The special assistant to the UN
Secretary-General, U. Thant, stat
ed that he had been involved with
the Congo situation during the
last three and a half years and
that his assignment was much
more demanding and complex
than his Palestine assignment. He
is positive that peace will pre
vail in the Congq.
Biting heavily into his topic, “UN
- Criticisms and Prospects,” Dr.
Bunche assured the aadience that
UN was at present the world’s best
means of avoiding total devasta
« uoo. He added that there was no
t better means in the world of pre
venting war and working for the
betterment of all.
He urged the audience to reject
hearsay, half-truth and the casual
observations of prejudiced people
and to judge UN purely on its rec
ord - its true record.
Facing the critics of UN square
ly, Dr. Bunche answered the fre
quent criticism of Communist
domination. He stated that there
is no record in the history of the
UN of a Communist block victory
in voting. He said that it is in
teresting to note that the Commun
ists accused the UN of being im
perialist dominated.
; At times Dr. Bunche injected
pure humor into his talk. He cit
ed the mid-western school teacher
who spent many days studying the
UN in action. Her conclusion was,
“It is a wonderful organization,
but it is full of so many foreign
ers.”
Answering the most heated cri
ticism evolving around the UN’s
action in the Congo, Dr. Bunche
gave the following documented
facts: (1) UN was in the Congo
and Katanga on the express invi
tation of the official Congo govern
ment. (2> The Congo government
is neither left nor right, but was
desperately seeking to bring or
der out of chaos. (3) In a Demo
cratic election, held in Katanga
providence, the overwhelming
vote was against secession. (4)
Dr. Bunche was with Mr. Tshombe
in Brussels on the occasion of the
signing of the documents guaran
teeing independeftce. and he stat
ed there was no hint of dissatis
faction. Dr. Bunche informed the
first Institutional Church
; 'f&J ■-''>■& • wMhy... '
GRAND OPENING OF NEW CHURCH BUILD
ING The above picture is a likeness of the new
First Institutional Baptist Church, 1141 East
Jefferson Street, soon to be completed. The
Grand Opening of the series of Dedication and
he arrived here at the airport. He stated this
w'as his first time this has happened to him at
an airport. Dr. Bunche spoke at a forum at
Temple Beth Israel that night.
(SUN Photo - James Boozer)
DR. RALPH BUNCHE
Special Assistant to the
Secretary-General of the UN
audience that Mr. Tshombe spent
much of his time discussing the
Articles' of Confederation of the
early American government.
Giving a human touch to the Ka
tanga situation, Dr. Bunche stat
ed that the general population re
ceived the UN forces with enthus
iasm and welcome.
It was Dr. Bunche’s studied op
inion that Mr. Tshombe’s action
sprang from outside influences
which were related to the rich min
eral resources in Katanga and did
not spring from the people them
selves. This is why, according to
Dr. Bunche, the secession failed.
Keene Brown To Be
Honored At Banquet
Keene S. Brown, who has re
signed as secretary of the Ari
zona State Federation of Labor,
AFL-CIO, is moving to San Fran
cisco, with his family, to take
over his new position as an ex
ecutive in the Western Greyhound
Bus Corporation.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87065526/1963-10-24/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1963&sort=relevance&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&index=10&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=ralph+bunche&y=10&x=13&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=2</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Bunche Speaks
In State; Hits
At Gov. Barnett
JACKSON (UPI) - Ralph
Bunche, undersecretary of the
United Nations, expressed con
fidence Wednesday night that
many white Mississippians are
“not so ignorant of our national
situation” as Gov. Ross Barnett.
The Negro diplomat was re
ferring to Barnett’s refusal to
recognize United Nations Day,
which is being observed today
elsewhere in the nation. Barn
ett feels the worldwide organi
zation is dominated by integra
tion-minded Socialists and Com
munists.
Bunche spoke at Tougaloo Col
lege, a predominantly Negro in
stitution eight miles from the
state capital, and commented
that he was “within shouting
distance of the heathens.’*
“Nowhere are the principles
upon which the United Nations
was founded as sorely needed
as they are in the state of Mis
sissippi,” he said.
Dozens of white students and
adults joined several hundred
Negro students in the capacity
crowd which heard Bunche at
the school which has been
termed a “cancer” in this seg
regation stronghold by Mayor
Allen Thompson. Bunche ex
pressed pleasure at this in
stance of intergation in Missis
sippi.
He predicted that most white
Southerners would be relieved if
integration were complete and
racial tensions eradicated.
Bunche charged that Barnett,
in his fight against integration,
had caused “an awful lot of
harm to our country’s image
and prestige.”
Bunche said the United Na
tions is “overwhelmingly and
solidly against racial discrimin
ation” and has “sympathy for
the American Negro in his
heroic struggle for equality.”
However, Bunche said he
did not believe the United
States should make changes on
the racial front simply to please
other nations. Changes should
be made, he said, because of a
“moral duty.”
Bunche also attacked a Jack
son newspaper columnist who
was critical of him and the
United Nations. The columnist,
said Bunche, “suffers acutely
from malignant affliction of
mind and heart known as
bigotry.”</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88077225/1951-04-03/ed-1/seq-3/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1960-07-17/ed-1/seq-131/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>Lovolty of Dr. Ralph
‘Bunche Unanimously
‘Upheld After Probe ' |
Dr. Ralph"‘]. ‘Bunche, the
highest ranking American in
the United Nations adminis
tration was cleared by unani
mounly by the Loyalty Board
of the United States, follow
‘ ing an investigation = into
charges against him as to hav
ing had Red affiliation.
“There is no doubt as to the
loyalty of Dr. Bunche to the
government of the United
‘States,”’the decision of the In
térnational Organizations’ Em
ployees’ Loyalty Board stated.
Dr. Bunche, who is princi
pal director of the UN.s
Trusteeship is scheduled to be
appointed as the second-rank
ing administrative officer. in
the world organization and its
itop trouble-shooter. '
i e SR N T S et ——</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2019270505/1950-04-27/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037526/1955-08-22/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=5&rows=20&words=BUNCHE+Bunche+Ralph+RALPH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Dr. Ralph Bunche
Calls Atomic Talks |
“Highly Successful”
Dr. Ralph J. Bunche, Under
Secretary of the United Na-’
tions returned-to the United
States yesterday from Gene
va, where he attended the
recent talks' on the peaceful
uses of atomic energy. He wasi
accompanied by Admiral
Lewis E. Strauss, chairman of
the Atomic Energy Commis-f
sion, who also attended the
gOnference. .&r o e , I
' Dr. Bunche said that the!
talks were highly successful. ’
It wag very gratifying to th_e|
United Nations that the.con-[
ference was characterized by
such a fine spirit throughout.
It was an excellent example
of international cooperation.
Questioned by newsmen
about the attitude of the Rus-‘
sians, Dr. Bunche said that the
cooperation was universal on
the part of all participants.
He indicated that it was like—]
ly that a similar meeting will
'be held in two o rthree years.
Dr. Bunche was a recipient
o fthe Nobel peace prize,
MONDAY, AUGUST 22, 1955
' Herbert Olsen, Is
'Named Historian for
Nat’l Historic Site
Herbert Olsen, who was
appointed Historian for the
National Historic Site arrived
here over the last week-end to
take up his duties. He was ac
companied by Hareld A. Hub
ler, Superintendent of the Na
tional- Historic Site in San
Juan, Puerto Rico. They were
welcomed by Administrator
D. C. Canegata.
Mr, Herbert, a native of
Denmark, will have temporary
'offices in Government House.
iHe will, among other things,
‘guide, lecture, place signs,
-markers and other facilities
‘needed for intei‘pre_ting the
‘'site to visitors. a
| In addition to research and
preparation of liferature .for
distribution, Mr, Olsen will
cooperate, with local officials
in the preservation and main
\tenance of the Site.
| e</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037548/1955-01-13/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037526/1954-07-06/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=8&rows=20&words=BUNCHE+Bunche+Ralph+RALPH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DR. RALPH BUNCHE
R e e aree) __‘, v .._‘: e
U. S. Justice Dept.
to Probe Accusers of
Dr. Ralph Bunche
' The United States Depart
ment of Justice has been ask
ed to probe the accusers of
Dr .Ralph Bunche which could
result in action for purjury.
This action was taken by the
chairman of the International
Organization Employees Loy
|alty Board. This Board is the
one set up to test the loyalty
of American employees of the
United Nations. |
' After being accused by two
ex-communists, Manning John
son and Leonard Pattefson,
the six members found that
there was absolutely no doubt
as to the loyalty of the dis
tinguished Negro leader who
was the successful mediator
between Israel and the Arab</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037526/1949-01-13/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Leaders Meet With |
Dr. Ralph Bunche |
- Egyptian and Jewish repre
sentatives met on the Island of
F.hodes today under the chair
rnanship of Dr. Ralph Bunche
to begin talks on ending the
war in Palestine. It was the
first time that such talks had
ever been attempted between
the two. e
Dr. Bunche has asked all
parties to refrain from any
acts that would endanger a
peaceful settlement. ‘
One of the British pilots
that was shot down said that
the planes had crossed into
Jewish territory, for the pur
pose of photographing Jewish
positions. He did not know
whether or not the flight lead
er had had instructions to
cross the border. |
“CHAMPION OF PUBLIC RIGHT AND JUSTICE" |
Council To Convene
‘Next Tues.; 5 Items
| An extra-ordinary meeting
of the Municipal Council of
St. Croix has been convened
for next Tuesday, January 18,;
at 10:30 a.m. by the Chairman,l
the Honorable Ludvig E. Har
rigan. ‘
On the agenda is five items,
‘among them a bill to abolish!
the council’s “Committee on
Investigations” and another
calling for conducting an in
vestigating of all Municipall
Departments.
British Ambassador
Confers With
President Truman
- British ambassador, Sir Oli
ver Franks, met with Presi
‘dent Truman to discuss the
Palestine situation and inform
the U.S. of British policy and
learn ©f the American atti
tude. The previous day he call
ed at the State Department &
~discussed the situation with
| Acting Secretary of State Ro
!bert Lovett.
| The British government in
[the meantime has issued a
| statement saying that the
‘word of Dr. Ralph Bunche,
Acting Mediator in Palestine
has been accepted and that all
Jewish troops have been with
drawn from Egypt.
India, Pakistan Agree
On Plebecite by UN
l Complete agreement . has
been reported between the do-!
minions of India and Pakistan
on plans to hold a plebecite in
Kashmir under the supervi
sion of United Nations offi-,
cials. Commissions are set up
to deal with refugees and eva
cuee, problems, dealing with
propety left behind. I
It was the second confer-.
ence between the two which
has ended in complete agree
ment.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83004231/1951-04-21/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=10&rows=20&words=BUNCHE+Bunche+Ralph+RALPH&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>RALPH BUNCHE BENEFACTOR
We have read much about Ralph Bunche the diplomat and med
iator. This is to introduce Ralph Bunche the benefactor. The pages of
the press of the nation have within recent months lauded Ralph
Bunche to the skies with a praise that has been justly deserved. As
Nqbel Prize winner, as mediator in the crucial Palestine disputes, Dr.
Bunche has wrung from a color-struck world words of highest com
mendation.
While Negro athletes have astounded the world of sports with
their athletic prowess and while the world has sung praises of our
athletic heroes, it was fitting that notice be served on the world that
Negroes were great in other fields than athletics and the boxing pro
fessions so eminently distinguished by the inimitable Joe Louis and
the Sugar Ray Robinson of pugilistic fame.
Just as a wondering world was about to accord us a place in the
world of sports and leave us there, Dr. Ralph Bunche appeared on the
scene and established beyond a reasonable doubt that Negroes rate as
diplomats and statesmen. The achievements of Dr. Bunche have
served as a moral tonic to allay any doubts that the Negro is not only
a man. but a versatile man, equal to all emergencies. Being a man of
great learning and hailing from fair Harvard’s historic halls, Dr.
Bunche knows what to say and how to say it.
‘As a recent speaker at the University of Virginia, founded by the
Illustrious Thomas Jefefrson, Dr. Bunche delivered himself in mag
nificient fashion to 1.500 students and faculties that were amazed at
his words of wisdom. Dr. Bunche was not disagreeable and disgruntled
as he laid before that august assembly facts pertaining to race rela
tions in this country.
He simply applied his vast wisdom and knawledge in diplomatic
but unmistabable language that held his audience spell-bound and
left them in stern amazement. To quote him: “America cannot have
two brands of democracy, pure or first-quality democracy for export
and an imperfect factory-second quality for home consumption.”
“The freedom-loving world looks to us for Jeadership in demon
strating the virility of the democratic way of life, not its profession
but its practice and application.”—“To the realistic, even cynical,
world of today, profession has its meaning only in deed. We cannot
convert the masses of Asia and Africa to a democracy qualified by
color. Even Europe is not a little baffled by that type of democracy.”
In concluding his address, he said that “the United States must
consider not only how we look on the rest of the world but also how
the rest of the world looks on us and how it measures American
standard of democracy.” Dr. Bunche’s address amounts to one of the
mots powerful pronouncements of the Twentieth Century. He said
the right things in the right way and to the right audience. They are
going to be like seed sown in good ground. The truth in that pro
nouncement may be crushed to earth but it will rise again.
Even while Dr. Bunche spoke his words of wisdom, the white
Baptist seminaries of the south were tearing asunder the segregation
al partititions that have barred Negroes theological study in the Bap
tist seminaries of the south. Truly jugement should begin at the house
of the Lord. This writer made some years ago a study of the White
seminaries of the south and was startled to know that the southern
Baptist seminaries had more students than all the combined semin
aries of the rest of the nation.
In other words it was evident that White Baptist preachers of the
nation of tomorrow will have been trained in the south and its tra
ditions. Great fear was evoked that these would not only preach
Christ, but also southern tradition, which in the last analysis is anti-
Christian and anti-Negro. But how changed the picture when south
ern seminaries lay off segregation!
What is quite as important as the abandonment of segregation is
the fact that it was done voluntarily. There were now lawsuits, no
intervention by the NAACP. no national controversy. The southern
Whites for the first time in their history, made a notable voluntary
concession in the interest of Christianity and democracy. Though mote
it be!</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025247/1951-04-20/ed-1/seq-5/#date1=1756&index=12&rows=20&words=Bunche+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ralph Bunche Is Benefactor
Dean Gordon Hancock Says
By Dean Gordon B Hancock
Richmond, Va.—We have read
much about Ralph Bunche. the
diplomat and mediator. This is to
introduce Ralph Bunche the bene
factor. The pages of the press of
the nation have within recent
months lauded Ralph Bunche to
the skies with a praise that has
been Justly deserved. As Nobel
Prise winner, as mediator in the
crucial Palestine disputes. Dr
Bunche has wrung from a color
struck world, words of highest
commendation
While Negro athletes have as
tounded the world of sports with
their athletic prowess and while
the world has sung praises of our
athletic heroes, it was fitting that
notice be served on the world
that Negroes were great in other
fields than athletics and the box
ing professions so eminently dis
tinguished by the inimitable Joe
Louis and the Sugar Ray Robin
son of pugilistic fame.
Just as a wondering world was
about to accord us a place in the
world of sports and leave us there,
Dr. Ralph Bunche appeared on the
scene and established beyond a
reasonable doubt that Negroes
rate high as diplomats and states
men. The achievements of Dr
Bunche have served as a moral
tonic to allay any doubts that the
Negro is not only a man, but a
versatile man, equal to all emer
gencies. Being a man of great
learning and hailing from fair
Harvard’s historic halls Dr
Bunche knows what to say and
how to say it.
As a recent speaker at the
University of Virginia, founded
by the Illustrious Thomas Jef
ferson. Dr. Bunche delivered
himself In magnificent fashion
to 1.500 students and faculties
that were amazed at his words
of wisdom. Dr. Bunche was not
disagreeable and disgruntled as
hr laid before that august as
sembly facts pertaining to race
relations in this country
He simply applied his vast wis
dom and knowledge in diplomatic
but unmistakable language that
held his audience spell-bound and
left them in stern amazement.
To quote him: “America cannot
have two brands of democracy, a
pure or first-quality democracy
for export and an Imperfect fac
tory-second quality for home con-
I > '"
B far JUST KIGHT Washing Every Tiwl
f AUTOMATIC yf j
| rfcCMdtfo
Matter-minds ths |ob. Times / flffl
I washing, shuts off machine, J|
rings bell. Ends dingy under- \
H washing, harmful over-washing I fclvut
i W I
I 1
I Sa/ifxflw ™ j I
H ACTION
■ Surges het, sudsy water up, iZI <■
Em dawn, around—throughout ev- / ®
I ery part of every garment. As-
I sures totai cleansing. Harder / I >
■ on dirt, easier on clothes. 9 f
ibmebmiiiniiii -
B s 164 55 I
tit WHIILPOOL AT
BROADWAY FURNITURE
ANO APPIIANCI
3033 Woo* BrwAwery
sumption.’
The freedom-loving world
looks to us for leadership in dem
onstrating the virility of the
democratic way of life, not its
profession but its practice and ap
plication " To the realistic,
even cynical, world of today, pro
fession has its meaning only in
deed. We cannot convert the
masses of Asia and Africa to a
democracy qualified by color
Even Europe is not a little baffled
by that type of democracy ”
In concluding his address, he
said that "the United States must
consider not only how we look on
the rest of the world, but also
the rest of the world looks on us
and how it measures American
standards of democracy." Dr
Bunches address amounts to one
of the most powerful pronounce
ments of the 20th Century. He
said the right things tn the right
way and to the nght audience.
Even while Dr. Bunche spoke
his words of wisdom, the white
Baptist seminaries of the south
were tearing asunder the segrega
tions! partitions that have barred
Negroes theological study in the
Baptist seminaries of the south
Truly judgement should begin at
the house of the Lord. This writer
made some years ago a study of
the white seminaries of the south
and was startled to know that the
three southern Baptist seminaries
had more students than all the
combined seminaries of the rest of
the nation</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037526/1956-06-08/ed-1/seq-1/#date1=1756&index=13&rows=20&words=Bunche+BUNCHE+RALPH+Ralph&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Ralph+Bunche&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DR. RALPH J. BUNCHE
! Dr. Ralph J. Bunche, Under
.secretary of the United Na
tions was of the several
‘distinguished gentlemen to re
‘ceive honorary degrees from
New York University at its
commencement exercises on
Wednesday.
The degreé of Honorary
Doctor of Laws were confer
red on Dr. Bunche, Clarence
D. Dillon, American' Ambas
sador to France, Judge Anna
M. Kross of New York and
others.
Citizens Urged to
Join White House
Conference Comm.
| The St. Croix member of
,The White House Conference
Committee will form the nu
'cleus of a Citizen’s Committee
lon Education, according to an
‘a’npouncement made by Mrs.
lPearl B. Larsen, Director of
|Special Activities of the De
’partment of Edueation. Invi
ltations have been sent out
asking citizens to join.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
